A famous man once said,
有位名人曾经说过
"We create our own demons."
"我们创造了自己的恶魔"
Who said that? What does that even mean?
究竟是谁说的? 这意味着什么?
It doesn't matter. I said it because he said it.
并不重要 因为他说了 我也说了
So, now, he was famous
所以 既然他很出名
and it's basically getting said by two well-known guys.
现在 那么这句话就有两个名人说过了
I don't...
我不...
I'm going to start again.
我再来一遍
Let's track this from the beginning.
我们还是重头开始吧
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 咳嗽的小鱼 捞盐 ICL的RK翔 海盗爱热水 千欲 汐颜
校对: 柚子茶 影子
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 咳嗽的小鱼 捞盐 ICL的RK翔 海盗爱热水 千欲 汐颜
校对: 柚子茶 影子
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 咳嗽的小鱼 捞盐 ICL的RK翔 海盗爱热水 千欲 汐颜
校对: 柚子茶 影子
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 咳嗽的小鱼 捞盐 ICL的RK翔 海盗爱热水 千欲 汐颜
校对: 柚子茶 影子
瑞士 伯尔尼
新年前夕
Half hour till the ball drops.
还有半小时就迈入新年了
- Hey, do you wanna...  - Tony Stark?
- 嘿 你想...  - 托尼・斯塔克?
- Great speech, man!  - I got you, pal.
- 讲的真棒 伙计!  - 找到你了 老兄
I gave a speech? How was it?
我刚才的演讲? 怎么样?
- Edifying.  - Unintelligible.
- 大受启发  - 令人费解
Really? It's my favourite kind. A winning combo.
真的吗? 我就喜欢这样 不败王道
- Where are we going?  - To town, on each other.
- 我们这是去哪?  - 找找乐子 二人世界
Probably back in your room
也许回你房间
because I also want to see your research.
因为我也想瞧瞧你的研究成果
Okay, you can see my research,
好的 你可以看我的成果
but that's... I'm not gonna show you my "town."
但... 你可不许乱来
Mr Stark.
斯塔克先生
Ho Yinsen.
我是侯・银森
I finally met a man called "Ho."
我终于认识一个姓"侯"的人了
I would like to introduce you to our guest, Dr Wu.
我想给你介绍我的一位客人 吴博士
- Oh, this guy.  - Mr Stark.
- 噢 是他  - 斯塔克先生
You're a heart doctor. She's going to need a cardiologist after I...
您是心脏病医生 这位小姐呆会儿需要您急救
Perhaps another time?
那我们下次再聚?
It started in Bern, Switzerland. 1999.
一切从瑞士伯尔尼 1999年开始
- The old days.  - Mr Stark!
- 那些日子  - 斯塔克先生!
I never thought they would come back to bite me.
从没想过会变成日后的恶梦
Why would they?
为什么会这样?
Wow! Hey, Tony!
哇! 嘿 托尼!
Aldrich Killian. I'm a big fan of your work.
我是阿尔德里奇・基利安 十分仰慕您的成果
- My work?  - Who isn't? He means me.
- 我的成果?  - 他指的是我
Of course, but Ms Hansen,
当然 汉森小姐
my organisation's been tracking your research since year two of MIT.
从你在麻省理工二年级的时候 我们机构就在关注你的研究了
Yeah, we're full.
是的 我们满了
Wow, he made it. He made the cut.
哇 他进来了 成功挤进来了
What floor you going to, pal?
伙计 你去几楼?
Well, now, that is an appropriate question.
哇 这个问题问的好
The ground floor, actually,
实际上 我去底层
of a proposal I'm putting together myself.
就像我一样 刚刚起步
It's a privately funded think tank called.
这是个私人赞助的智囊团
She'll take both. One to throw away and one to not call.
她两张都要 一张扔了 一张永远不会理会
"Advanced Idea Mechanics," or "AIM," for short. Do you get it?
叫"先进概念力学研究所" 简称AIM 记住了吗?
I see that, because it's on your T-shirt.
我看见了 T恤上写着呢
Ladies, follow the mullet. Ladies first.
女士们 跟着大乌鱼走 女士优先
Thank you, I'll call you.
谢谢 我会打给你
I'm titillated by the notion of working with you.
我很有兴趣聊聊你的工作
- Yeah?  - I'll ditch these clowns.
- 真的吗?  - 等我甩开这些小丑
I'll see you up on the roof in five minutes.
五分钟后楼顶见
Just gonna try and get my beak wet real quick.
等我先去润润喉
You know what I'm talking about?
明白我的意思了吗?
I'll see you up there.
那我们楼顶见
Damn betcha.
不见不散
Come on! I thought that was just a theory.
了不起! 我还以为只是个理论
Well, it was.
曾经是
If I'm right, we can access the area of the brain
要是我的理论没错 我们就能进入大脑
- that governs repair...  - Wow.
- 修复中枢...  - 哇
and chemically recode it.
用化学试剂重新编码
That's incredible. Essentially, you're hacking into the genetic...
太不可思议了 从本质来说 你入侵了生物...
operating system of a living organism
遗传运作系统
Exactly.
没错
- Yes.  - Wow.
- 是的  - 哇
Is that... Can you...
它是... 你能不能...
- What?  - Can you not touch my plant?
- 怎么了?  - 别碰我的植物?
It's not... She doesn't like it. She prefers...
她讨厌被碰 她喜欢...
She's not like the others. Come on. Let's go in the bedroom.
她不喜欢陌生人 来吧 我们去卧室聊
- Happy...  - That's cute...
- 哈皮...  - 真可爱...
Leave her ficus alone.
别惹她的植物
Because. And, no, seriously, don't.
因为 而且 不 我说真的 别惹她
- And you're starting with plants.  - For now, yeah.
- 你已经开始在植物上实验了  - 目前来说 是的
I'm calling it EXTREMIS.
我管它叫终极生物
- Well, it's...  - Human application.
- 好吧 它是...  - 最终用于人类
Exactly, exactly.
没错 说的对
- Dendritic revitalisation.  - It's revolutionary.
- 树枝修复  - 这将是革命性的
- Disease prevention...  - Change the world.
- 预防疾病...  - 改变世界
even limb regrowth.
甚至是肢体再生
You're the most gifted woman I've ever met.
你是我见过最有天赋的女人
Wow.
哇
- In Switzerland.  - That's better.
- 我是说在瑞士见过的  - 这么说好多了
- You're seeing things.  - This week.
- 你能看见  - 这个星期
You almost bought it, didn't you?
你差点就上当了 对吗?
This is what I'm talking about, the glitch.
这就是我给你说过的小问题
Have you checked the telomerase algorithm?
检查过端粒酶算法吗?
- The what?  - Down!
- 什么?  - 趴下!
Stay down! Stay down, boss.
趴下别动! 别动 老板
- We're good.  - Stay down.
- 我们没事  - 别动
You're right on me. I made it.
你压在我身上 我没法动
What the hell was that?
究竟发生了什么事?
- What was that?  - It's a glitch in my work. It's...
- 怎么回事?  - 这是我研究的一点小故障 它...
She was just talking about it. Glitches happen.
她刚刚说过 会有故障发生
It's not Y2K.
不是千年虫
Hey! Happy New Year!
嘿! 新年快乐!
- Happy New Year.  - Happy New Year.
- 新年快乐  - 新年快乐
All right. I'll see you in the morning. Good night.
好的 明早见 晚安
- You good?  - Yeah.
- 你没事吧?  - 没事
- I'll be right outside.  - Okay, cool.
- 我就在外面  - 好的 没事
So, why am I telling you this?
那么 为什么要和你们说这名言?
Because I had just created demons
因为我那时创造了恶魔
and I didn't even know it.
而我当时却浑然不知
Yeah, those were good times.
是啊 那是段美好的时光
Then I moved on.
不过我放下了
After a brief soiree in an Afghan cave, I said goodbye to the party scene.
经历阿富汗某个洞穴里的一个聚会后 我告别了派对
I forgot that night in Switzerland.
也忘记了那晚在瑞士发生的一切
现在 加利福利亚 马里布
- These days, I'm a changed man.  - Forty-six.
- 现在 我变了个人  - 46
I'm different now.
和以前不一样了
I'm... Well...
我... 好吧...
- Forty-seven.  - You know who I am.
- 47  - 你知道我是谁
Sir, please may I request just a few hours to calibrate...
主人 可以再给我几个小时 我就能校准...
No. Forty-eight.
不 48
Micro-repeater implanting sequence complete.
微型感应装置植入完毕
As you wish, sir.
如您所愿 主人
I've also prepared a safety briefing for you to entirely ignore.
我还为您准备了个安全简报 当然您不会听
Which I will.
当然不听
All right, let's do this.
好吧 我们开始
DUM-E.
大E
Hi, DUM-E.
大笨蛋
How did you get that cap on your head? You earned it.
你头上的帽子哪弄的? 真是名副其实
Hey. Hey!
嘿 嘿!
What are you doing out of the corner? You know what you did.
还藏在那个角落做什么? 你知道你做了什么好事
Blood on my mat. Handle it.
地毯上的血迹 弄干净
Sir, may I remind you that you've been awake for nearly 72 hours?
主人 恕我提醒 您已经72小时没合眼了?
Focus up, ladies.
注意啦 女士们
Good evening, and welcome to the birthing suite.
晚上好 欢迎来到生产基地
I am pleased to announce the imminent arrival
我很荣幸地宣布 你们又多了一位
of your bouncing, bad-ass baby brother.
活波 可爱的宝贝兄弟
Start tight and then go wide.
先特写 再全景
Stamp date and time.
打上时间和日期
Mark 42. Autonomous prehensile propulsion suit test.
第42代自适应导航装备 测试开始
lnitialise sequence.
启动程序
Jarvis, drop my needle.
贾维斯 来点音乐
Crap.
废物
All right, I think we got this. Send them all.
好的 这个行了 全都来吧
Probably a little fast. Slow it down.
有点快了 慢一点
Slow it down just a...
慢一点...
little bit.
一点点
Cool it, will you, Jarvis?
轻一点 行不行 贾维斯?
Come on. I ain't scared of you.
来吧 我可不怕你
I'm the best.
我是最棒的
As always, sir, a great pleasure watching you work.
一如既往 主人 看你工作真是赏心悦目
I guess 72 hours is a long time between siestas.
我想72个小时是有点太久了
I didn't think it could get any worse.
没想过情况会变得更糟
Then I had to go and turn on the TV.
但我打开电视
That's when he happened.
他就这样出现了
Some people call me a terrorist.
有人说我是恐怖分子
I consider myself a teacher.
我认为自己是个老师
America.
美国
Ready for another lesson?
准备好上另一堂课了吗?
In 1864, in Sand Creek, Colorado, the US military waited
1864年 科罗多州沙溪 美国部队等待所有友好的
until the friendly Cheyenne braves had all gone hunting.
夏安族勇士出去打猎 等待
Waited to attack and slaughter the families left behind
袭击和屠杀他们的家人
and claim their land.
然后抢占他们的土地
39 hours ago,
39小时前
the Ali AI Salem Air Base in Kuwait was attacked.
科威特阿里艾勒姆空军基地被袭击了
I... I... I did that.
我... 我... 是我干的
A quaint military church
那是个挤满女人与孩子的
filled with wives and children, of course.
古老军事教堂
The soldiers were out on manoeuvres.
士兵们出外演习
The braves were away.
勇士们都不在
President Ellis.
埃利斯总统
You continue to resist my attempts to educate you, sir.
你仍然在拒绝我的教导 先生
And now you've missed me again.
现在你又再次无视我
You know who I am.
你知道我是谁
You don't know where I am.
但不知道我在哪儿
And you'll never see me coming.
永远无法预料我何时到来
Now that we seem to be back,
既然信号又回来了
let's recap some of the frightening developments...
让我们回顾几起恐怖袭击...
American airwaves were hijacked...
美国广播被黑客入侵...
The nation remains on high alert.
整个国家处于高度戒备中
All attempts to find the Mandarin have so far proved unsuccessful.
到目前为止 所有追捕满大人的行动 仍然毫无进展
Central to my administration's response to this terrorist event
内阁对这起恐怖事件的对应办法是
is a newly minted resource.
这种新崛起的资源
I know him as Colonel James Rhodes.
我知道 他是詹姆斯・罗迪上校
The American people will soon know him
对所有美国人来说他将是
as the Iron Patriot.
钢铁爱国者
And how is President Ellis responding?
这就是总统的回应?
By taking the guy they call War Machine
找来那个被他们称为机甲战士的家伙
and giving him a paint job.
重新喷漆
The same suit, but painted red, white and blue.
同一套盔甲 涂成红 白 还有蓝色
Look at that. And they also renamed him, "lron Patriot."
瞧瞧 还给他取了个新名字 "钢铁爱国者"
You know, just in case the paint was too subtle.
你知道 为了防止油漆太脆弱了
It tested well with focus groups, all right?
民意反馈效果不错 对吗?
"I am Iron Patriot!" it sucks.
"我是钢铁爱国者!" 这名字真烂
"War Machine" was a little too aggressive.
"机甲战士" 又有点过了
All right? This sends a better message.
对吗? 这个听着还不错
So, what's really going on? With the Mandarin.
那么 究竟发生了什么事? 满大人何许人
Seriously, can we talk about this guy?
说真的 能聊聊这家伙吗?
It's classified information, Tony.
这是机密信息 托尼
Okay, there have been nine bombings.
好吧 一共有9起爆炸
- Nine.  - The public only knows about three.
- 9起  - 群众只知道3起
But here's the thing, nobody can ID a device.
问题的关键是 没有人能找到他们使用的设备
There's no bomb casings.
没有炸弹壳体
You know I can help. Just ask.
你知道我能帮上忙 只要找我
I got a ton of new tech. I got a prehensile suit.
我有一堆高科技 自适应导航装备
I got bomb disposal. It catches explosions in mid-air.
我还有拆弹设备 能在空中捉住炸弹
When's the last time you got a good night's sleep?
上次你睡个好觉是什么时间?
Einstein slept three hours a year. Look what he did.
爱因斯坦一年只睡3小时 瞧瞧他的成就
People are concerned about you, Tony. I'm concerned about you.
托尼 大家都很担心你 我也很担心你
You're going to come at me like that?
你也会担心我?
I'm not trying to be a dick...
我可不想表现的像个混...
Tator.
蛋
Do you mind signing my drawing?
可以给我签个名吗?
If Richard doesn't mind. Are you all right with this, Dick?
要是罗迪不介意的话 蛋蛋 你介意吗?
Yeah. Fine with me.
不 我随意
- What's your name?  - Erin.
- 你叫什么?  - 艾尔琳
I loved you in A Christmas Story, by the way.
顺便说一句 你长得像圣诞节故事里的人
Listen, the Pentagon is scared.
听着 五角大楼那边吓坏了
After New York, aliens... Come on.
经过纽约事件 外星人... 拜托
They need to look strong.
他们得表现得强大
Stopping the Mandarin is a priority, but it's not...
现在我们的首要任务是阻止满大人 但是...
- it's not superhero business.  - No, it's not, quite frankly.
- 这不是超级英雄管的事  - 当然不是 坦白说的
- I get it.  - It's American business.
- 我懂了  - 这是国家的事
That's why I said I got it.
所以我说我懂了
Are you okay?
你还好吗?
I broke the crayon.
我把蜡笔毁了
Are you okay, Mr Stark?
你没事吧 斯塔克先生?
Take it easy. Tony.
放松 托尼
How did you get out of the Wormhole?
你怎么从虫洞逃出来的?
Wait a minute. Tony!
等等 托尼!
- What did you say?  - Tony.
- 你刚才说什么?  - 托尼
Sorry.
抱歉
I'm just checking on the suit.
我得检查下盔甲
Okay.
好的
Check the heart.
检查心脏
Is it the brain?
是大脑吗?
No sign of cardiac anomaly or unusual brain activity.
没有任何迹象显示心脏或大脑异常的迹象
Okay, so I was poisoned?
好的 那我中毒了?
My diagnosis is that you've experienced a severe anxiety attack.
诊断结果显示您极度焦虑
Me?
我?
Come on, man, this isn't a good look. Open up.
拜托 老兄 你这样子真难看 出来吧
Sorry, I gotta split.
对不起 我先撤了
Badge.
徽章
Come on, badge.
拜托 徽章
Badge, guys. I put a memo in the toilet. Come on.
徽章 伙计 我在洗手间贴了个备忘 拜托
Tony has got them in his basement. They're wearing party hats.
托尼的地下室有一堆装备 他们都戴着派对帽子
This is an asset that we can put to use.
这是笔我们可以动用的资产
So, you're suggesting that I replace the entire janitorial staff with robots.
你是在建议我把所有的清洁工都换成机器人
- Thank you.  - What I'm saying is that
- 谢谢  - 我的意思是
the human element of human resources is our biggest point of vulnerability.
在人力资源中 人是最薄弱的环节
We should start phasing it out immediately.
我们应该立即换掉
- What?  - Excuse me, Bambi,
- 什么?  - 抱歉 班比
- you should be wearing...  - Did you just say that?
- 你应该带徽章...  - 你刚刚说什么?
- Security? Yes?  - Happy? Okay.
- 安保? 是吗?  - 哈皮? 好
I am thrilled that you are now the Head Of Security. Okay?
我很高兴你现在是安保部门的头 好吗?
- It is the perfect position for you.  - Thank you.
- 这职位非常适合你  - 谢谢你
- However...  - I do appreciate it.
- 但是...  - 我很感谢
- since you've taken the post...  - You don't have to thank me.
- 自从你任职以后...  - 你不用谢我的
we've had a rise in staff complaints of 300%.
我的员工投诉率上涨了三倍
Thank you.
谢谢
It's not a compliment.
这不是恭维
It's not... It is a compliment.
这不是... 这是恭维
Clearly, somebody's trying to hide something.
很明显 有人在隐瞒什么
- I... Yes.  - Excuse me.
- 我... 是  - 打扰一下
Ms Potts, your 4:00 is here.
佩珀女士 四点您约好的人已经来了
- Thank you.  - Did you clear this 4:00 with me?
- 谢谢  - 四点的预约告诉过我吗?
Happy, we'll talk about this later,
哈皮 我们稍后再谈
but right now, I have to go deal with this very annoying thing.
但是现在 我要处理点棘手的事
How so?
什么事?
I used to work with him and he used to ask me out all the time,
我以前和他一起共过事 他总想约我出去
so it's a little awkward.
有点尴尬
I don't like the sound of that.
我也不喜欢这样
Pepper
佩珀
Killian?
基利安?
You look great.
气色不错
You look really great.
你看起来真棒
God, you look great.
天 你看起来真棒
I... I... I...
我... 我... 我...
What on earth have you been doing?
你最近在忙什么?
Nothing fancy.
没什么特别的
Just five years in the hands of physical therapists.
在理疗师那儿待了5年
And please, call me Aldrich.
请叫我阿尔德里奇
You were supposed to be issued a security badge.
你应该佩戴安保徽章
- Happy, it's okay. We're good.  - Yes.
- 哈皮 没事 我们很好  - 是的
- Are you sure? Okay.  - Yes. Stand down.
- 你确定? 好吧  - 是的 先回避下
- I'm going to linger right here. Okay.  - Thank you.
- 我去外面等候 好的  - 谢谢
It's very nice to see you, Killian.
很高兴见到你 基利安
Hey, guy
嘿 伙计
Merry Christmas.
圣诞节快乐
After years dodging the President's ban on "immoral" biotech research,
经过多年回避总统关于"不道德"生物科技研究的禁令
my think tank
我的智囊团
now has a little something in the pipeline.
总算研究酝酿了点小东西
It's an idea we like to call EXTREMIS.
我们把它叫做 终极生物
I'm gonna turn your lights down.
我先把灯关了
Regard the human brain.
关于人类大脑
Wait, hold on, hold on.
等等 稍等 等会
That's... That's the universe. My bad.
这是... 这是宇宙 搞错了
But if I do that...
应该换成这个...
That's the brain.
这是大脑
Strangely mimetic, though, wouldn't you say?
不可思议地相似 你不觉得吗?
Wow, that's amazing.
哇哦 太炫了
Thanks, it's mine.
多谢了 它是我的
What?
什么?
This. You're inside my head.
这个 你现在置身于我的脑中
It's a... It's a live feed.
它... 它在直播
Come on up, I'll prove it to you.
过来 我给你证实一下
Come on.
来嘛
Now, pinch my arm.
来 拧我的胳膊
I can take it. Pinch me.
我忍得住 来拧我
What is that?
那是什么?
It's the primary somatosensory cortex. It's the brain's pain centre.
那是主躯感皮质 是大脑的痛感中枢
But this is what I wanted to show you.
但这个才是我想给你看的
Now, EXTREMIS harnesses our bioelectrical potential
终极生物利用我们的生物电潜能
and it goes here.
一直到这儿
This is essentially an empty slot and what this tells us
这儿本质上就是一处空洞 而这告诉我们
is that our mind,
我们的头脑
our entire DNA, in fact,
我们的DNA系统
is destined to be upgraded.
注定要被改进
Wow.
哇
Wait...
等等...
Hello?
你好?
- Is this Forehead Of Security?  - What?
- 这里是额头保安部吗?  - 什么?
You know, look... I got a real job. What do you want?
你瞧... 我搞到一份货真价实的工作 你需要什么?
I'm working. I've got something going on, here.
我在工作 我手头正有活计 这儿
What, harassing interns?
什么 性骚扰实习生?
Let me tell you something. Do you know what happened
我跟你说 我跟别人说我曾是钢铁侠保镖的时候
when I told people I was Iron Man's bodyguard?
知道发生了什么吗?
They would laugh in my face.
他们都当面嘲笑我
I had to leave while I still had a shred of dignity.
趁着我还有一丝尊严尚存 我就得夺路而逃
Now I got a real job. I'm watching Pepper.
现在我搞到一份货真价实的工作 我在保护佩珀
What's going on? Fill me in.
怎么了? 跟我说说
- For real?  - Yeah.
- 真的?  - 嗯
All right. She's meeting up with this scientist.
好吧 她在跟这么一个科学家见面
- Rich guy. Handsome.  - Right.
- 有钱人 帅小伙  - 嗯
I couldn't make his face, at first. Right? You know I'm good with faces.
我一开始没认出来 但你知道我擅长认人的
- Yeah, you're the best.  - Yeah.
- 是啊 你最擅长了  - 嗯
Well, so I run his credentials. I make him.
于是我翻查了他的证件 我认出他来了
Aldrich Killian. We actually met the guy back in...
叫阿尔德里奇・基利安 我们其实见过这家伙
Where were we in '99? The science conference?
咱们99年在哪儿来着? 科学大会上?
- Switzerland.  - Right, right, exactly.
- 在瑞士  - 对对 的确如此
Killian. No... I don't remember that guy.
基利安 不... 我不记得这个人了
Of course you don't remember him. He's not a blond with a big rack.
你当然记不得他了 他又不是哪个金发大胸女
At first, it was fine. They were talking business.
一开始 还没什么 他们只是在谈公事
But now it's getting weird. He's showing her his big brain.
可现在事情诡异起来了 他开始给她看他的巨脑
- His what?  - Big brain.
- 他的什么?  - 巨脑
And she likes it. Here, let me show you.
而且她很欣赏 这儿 你看看
Hold on. See?
等等 看到没?
Look at what? You, watching them?
看到什么? 看你还是看他们?
Flip the screen, and then we can get started.
翻转屏幕 我才能看得到
I'm not a tech genius like you. Just trust me. Get down here.
我不像你是个技术天才 相信我就行了 快过来
Flip the screen. Then I can see what they're doing.
翻转屏幕 那样我就能看到他们在干什么了
I can't! I don't know how to flip the screen!
我不会! 我不知道怎么翻转屏幕!
Don't talk to me like that any more. You're not my boss.
别再这么跟我讲话 你不是我老板了
All right? I don't work for you.
行吗? 我不为你工作了
And I don't trust this guy. He's got another guy with him.
而且我不信任这家伙 他还带着另一个人
He's shifty.
那人贼眉鼠眼的
- Relax.  - Seriously?
- 放轻松  - 你确定?
I'm just asking you to secure the perimeter.
你现在保护住外围就好
Tell them to go out for a drink or something.
让他们出去喝杯东西什么的
You know what? You should take more of an interest in what's going on here.
你知道吗? 你应该对这儿正发生的事更上心一些
This woman's the best thing that ever happened to you
这个女人是你人生最美好的财富
and you're just ignoring her.
可你现在却无视她
- A giant brain?  - Yeah.
- 一个巨脑?  - 是啊
There's a giant brain. There's a shifty character.
有个巨脑 有个贼眉鼠眼的家伙
I'm gonna follow this guy. I'm gonna run his plates and I'm gonna...
我要跟踪这家伙 我要把他查个底朝天 我还要...
You know, if it gets rough, so be it.
要是得动粗 那就来吧
I miss you, Happy...
我想念你 哈皮...
Yeah, I miss you, too. But the way it used to be.
是啊 我也想念你 但是是以前那个你
Now you're off with the super-friends.
现在你都跟超级英雄哥们儿们厮混在一起
I don't know what's going on with you any more.
我都不知道你现在什么状况
- The world's getting weird.  - Hey!
- 整个世界都混乱了  - 嘿!
I hate to cut you off.
我真不想挂你电话
- Do you have your Taser on you?  - Why?
- 你的电击枪带身上没?  - 怎么?
I think there's a gal in H.R. who's trying to steal some printer ink.
我感觉人力资源部有个姑娘在偷打印机墨盒
You should probably go over there and zap her.
你或许该过那边去抓她个正着
Yeah, nice.
对哦 好极了
Imagine if you could hack into the hard drive of any living organism
想象一下 要是人能侵入任何有机体的硬盘
and recode its DNA.
并重组它的DNA
That would be incredible.
要是那样就好了
Unfortunately, to my ears, it also sounds highly weaponisable.
很不幸 在我听来 这项技术也很倾向于武器化
As in, enhanced soldiers, private armies, and Tony is...
比如改造战士和私人军队 而托尼...
Tony, Tony.
又是托尼 托尼
You know, I invited Tony to join AIM 13 years ago.
你知道吗 我13年前就邀请过托尼加入AIM公司
He turned me down.
他拒绝了我
But something tells me, now there's a new genius on the throne
但我看得出 现在有一位新生代的天才在宝座上
who doesn't have to answer to Tony any more
她不再需要受托尼的牵制了
and who has slightly less of an ego.
而且也不那么自我
It's gonna be a no, Aldrich.
我还是会说不 阿尔德里奇
As much as I'd like to help you.
尽管我非常愿意帮你
Well, I can't say that I'm not disappointed.
我得承认我大失所望
But then, as my father used to say,
但如我父亲一直所说
"Failure is the fog through which we glimpse triumph."
"透过失败的浓雾才能瞥见成功"
That's very deep.
很深奥
And I have no idea what it means.
听得我一头雾水
No, me neither. He was kind of an idiot, my old man.
我也是 他疯疯癫癫的 那老家伙
I'm sure I'll see you again, Pepper.
我相信我很快会再见到你的 佩珀
Happy...
哈皮...
Car's ready, if you're ready to go.
车备好了 准备好走了吗
Yes, I just...
是的 我还...
God, I forgot my other things, so...
天 我忘了还有其它事情 所以...
I'm just gonna...
我只能...
I'm sorry I'm late. I was...
抱歉我迟到了点 我在...
What the... What is that?
那... 那是什么?
You're wearing this in the house now?
你现在在屋子里都穿这个啦?
What is that, like, Mark 15?
这是第几代 马克15?
Yeah. Something like that. You know, everybody needs a hobby.
是啊 大概吧 人人都有嗜好
And you have to wear your hobby in the living room?
所以你在客厅穿上了你的嗜好?
Just breaking it in.
只是试穿
You know, it's always a little pinchy in the gooey bag at first, so...
刚穿上去总会感觉包得有点紧...
Well, hey, did you see your Christmas present?
嘿 你看到你的圣诞礼物了吗?
Yes, I did. I...
是的 我看到了...
I don't know how I could've missed that Christmas present.
我怎么可能注意不到那个圣诞礼物
Is it gonna fit through the door?
那东西进得了门吗?
Well, actually, it's a good question.
其实 这是个问题
I got a team of guys coming tomorrow. They're gonna blow out that wall.
我明天叫些人来 把那堵墙轰掉
- Okay.  - So...
- 好啊  - 那...
Tense? Good day? Huh?
紧张吗? 过得好吗今天? 嗯?
Shoulders, a little knotty. Naughty girl.
肩膀有点僵硬 调皮鬼
I don't want to harp on this, but did you like the custom rabbit?
我不想显得太絮叨 不过 你喜不喜欢那个定做的兔子?
Did I like it?
我喜不喜欢?
- Nailed it, right?  - Wow.
- 确定一下 行吧?  - 哇
I appreciate the thought very much.
这个想法很有创意
So, why don't you lift up that face mask and give me a kiss?
你干嘛不把那面具打开来吻我一下?
Yep. Damn it, no can do.
好啊 见鬼 打不开
You want to just kiss it on the... The facial slit?
你想不想就亲在... 面部夹缝这里?
Well, why don't I run down to the garage
要不我跑到车库里去
and see if I can't find a crowbar to jimmy that thing open?
找个撬棍把那玩意儿撬开来?
Crowbar, yeah.
撬棍 好啊
Except there's been a radiation leak.
只是那边有辐射泄漏
- I'll take my chances.  - That's risky.
- 我会碰碰运气的  - 太冒险了
At least, let me get you, like, a hazmat suit.
至少 让我给你拿件 防护盔甲之类的
A Geiger counter or something like that.
一个盖革计数器什么的
Busted.
被逮住了
- This is a new level of lame.  - Sorry.
- 你的花样还层出不穷了  - 抱歉
You ate without me already? On date night?
我还没来你就吃上了? 在约会这晚?
- He was just...  - You mean you.
- 他只是...  - 你是说你
Well, yeah, I just mean we were hosting you...
是啊 我只是说我们本想请你...
while I finished up a little work.
等我做完这点活儿
And yes, I had a quick bite.
的确 我简单吃了一口
I didn't know if you were coming home
我不知道你是要回家
or you were having drinks with Aldrich Killian.
还是跟阿尔德里奇・基利安喝酒去
- What?  - What?
- 什么?  - 什么?
Aldrich Killian? What, are you checking up on me?
阿尔德里奇・基利安? 什么 你在监视我?
Happy was concerned.
哈皮很担心
- You're spying on me.  - I wasn't.
- 你在监视我  - 我没有
- I'm going to bed.  - Hold on.
- 我要睡去了  - 等等
Come on. Pep?
别嘛 佩珀?
Hey, I admit it.
嘿 我承认
My fault. Sorry.
我的错 抱歉
I'm a piping hot mess.
我像热锅上的蚂蚁
It's been going on for a while. I haven't said anything.
已经有一阵子了 我什么也没说
Nothing's been the same since New York.
自从纽约那次以后一切都变了
Really? I didn't notice that at all.
真的? 我一点都没注意到
You experience things
人要是经历了一些事
and then they're over, and you still can't explain them.
然后这些事结束了 你却仍解释不通
Gods, aliens, other dimensions. I'm just a man in a can.
神 外星人 其它维度 我只是个罐中人
The only reason I haven't cracked up
我没有崩溃的唯一原因
is probably because you moved in.
可能就是因为你搬进来住了
Which is great.
搬得好
I love you. I'm lucky.
我爱你 我很幸运
But honey, I can't sleep.
可是亲爱的 我睡不着
You go to bed, I come down here. I do what I know.
你去睡觉 我就下这边来 我做我擅长的事
I tinker. I....
我修修补补 我...
Threat is imminent.
危机已迫在眉睫
And I have to protect the one thing that I can't live without.
而我必须保护好我唯一不能失去的
That's you.
那就是你
And my suits, they're...
而我的盔甲 它们是...
Machines.
机器
They're part of me.
它们是我的一部分
A distraction.
让你分心
Maybe.
或许吧
I'm gonna take a shower.
我得去洗个澡
Okay.
好吧
And you're gonna join me.
你跟我一起来
Better.
这样更好
Tony.
托尼
Tony. Tony.
托尼 托尼
To...
托...
Power down!
断电!
I must have called it in my sleep.
我肯定是梦里把它召唤过来的
That's not supposed to happen.
这种事不该发生的
I'll recalibrate the sensors.
我会重新校准传感器
Can we just... Just let me...
咱们能不能... 就让我...
Just let me catch my breath. Hey, don't... Don't go. All right? Pepper...
让我缓过这口气来 别走 好吗? 佩珀...
I'm going to sleep downstairs.
我要去楼下睡
Tinker with that.
你自己慢慢修修补补吧
Can you regulate?
你控制得了吗?
Yes, I can regulate.
是的 我能控制好
- You sure about that?  - Yes.
- 你确定?  - 确定
It's a decent batch.
很棒的一批货
- Don't say I never did nothing for you.  - Thank you.
- 可别说我没帮过你  - 多谢
I mean, for understanding.
我是说 感谢你的理解
I'm sorry, buddy.
真抱歉 老兄
What are you doing, buddy?
你干嘛呢 老兄?
You out by yourself? A little date night?
一个人出来? 小小的约会之夜?
Seeing your favourite chick flick, maybe?
或许还看了你最爱的纯情少女片?
Yeah, a little movie called The Party's Over,
是啊 一部叫做"到此为止"的电影
starring you and your junkie girlfriend.
你跟你的瘾君子女友主演
Here's the ticket.
这是电影票
No kidding. That doesn't belong to you.
说真的 那东西可不是你的
Savin!
赛文!
Help!
救命!
Help me!
帮帮我!
True story about fortune cookies.
幸运饼干真实的一面
They look Chinese.
它们看起来像中国的
They sound Chinese.
它们听起来像中国的
But they're actually an American invention.
但它们实际是美国的发明
Which is why they're hollow, full of lies
所以它们都很空洞 谎言连篇
and leave a bad taste in the mouth.
而且味道极差
My disciples just destroyed another cheap American knockoff.
我的信徒刚刚又毁掉了一个廉价的美国式复制品
The Chinese Theatre.
中国剧院
Mr President,
总统先生
I know this must be getting frustrating.
我知道您现在一定很泄气
But this season of terror is drawing to a close.
但这一轮的恐怖已经接近尾声了
And don't worry, the big one is coming.
别急 更精彩的就要来了
Your graduation.
您的毕业礼
Hi.
嗨
Do you mind leaving that on?
你不介意开着那个吧?
Sure.
当然不
Sunday nights. PBS. Downton Abbey.
星期天晚上 公共电视网 唐顿庄园
That's his show. He thinks it's elegant.
他最喜欢这部剧了 觉得风格很优雅
One more thing. Make sure everyone wears their badges.
还有件事 确保每个人都戴着他们的牌子
He's a stickler for that sort of thing.
他很看重这个
Plus, my guys won't let anyone in without them.
不戴牌子不让进
We're awaiting the arrival of Tony Stark.
我们正等待托尼・斯塔克的到来
We're hoping he'll give us the reaction...
我们希望他能给我们一个回应
His reaction to the latest attack.
他对最近一次袭击的回应
Mr Stark, hi there.
斯塔克先生 看这儿
Our sources are telling us that all signs are pointing to another Mandarin attack.
据称所有迹象都表明 这是满大人的新一轮袭击
Anything else you can tell us?
您还有什么可以告诉我们的?
Hey, Mr Stark. When is somebody gonna kill this guy?
斯塔克先生 什么时候能有人干掉这家伙?
I'm just saying.
我只是说说
Is that what you want?
这就是你想要的?
Here's a little holiday greeting
我有个小小的假日问候
I've been wanting to send to the Mandarin.
我一直等着送给满大人
I just didn't know how to phrase it until now.
我刚组织好了语言
My name is Tony Stark and I'm not afraid of you.
我叫托尼・斯塔克 我不怕你
I know you're a coward. So I've decided
我知道你是个懦夫 所以我决定
that you just died, pal.
你死定了
I'm gonna come get the body.
我会来给你收尸
There's no politics here. It's just good old-fashioned revenge.
这儿不谈什么政治 只是老规矩的复仇
There's no Pentagon, it's just you and me.
跟五角大楼无关 就是你和我
And on the off chance you're a man, here's my home address.
退一万步说 你要是个男人的话 这是我家地址
10880 Malibu Point.
马利布角10880弄
90265.
90265号
I'll leave the door unlocked.
我会大门敞开的
That's what you wanted, right?
这就是你想要的 是吧?
Bill me.
算我账上
I've compiled a Mandarin database for you, sir,
我编译了一个满大人的数据库给您 主人
drawn from S.H.l.E.L.D., FBI and CIA intercepts.
都是从神盾局 联邦调查局还有中情局拦截来的
Initiating virtual crime scene reconstruction.
启动虚拟犯罪现场重建
Okay. What have we got here?
好 我们都知道些什么?
The name is an ancient Chinese war mantle meaning "adviser to the king."
他名字是古代中国对战争谋士的称谓 意思是"国王的进谏者"
South American insurgency tactics.
南美叛乱战术
Talks like a Baptist preacher.
说话像个传教士
There's lots of pageantry going on here. Lots of theatre. Close.
事发之地在举行庆典 有很多剧院 关了
The heat from the blast was in excess of 3,000 degrees Celsius.
爆炸产生的热量超过了3000摄氏度
Any subjects within 12.5 yards were vaporised instantly.
12.5码以内的任何物体都瞬间蒸发了
No bomb parts found in a three-mile radius of the Chinese Theatre?
在中国剧院周围3英里内没有发现炸弹碎片?
No, sir.
没有 主人
Talk to me, Happy.
跟我说说吧 哈皮
When is a bomb not a bomb?
什么时候炸弹也不是炸弹了?
Any military victims?
有军人遇难吗?
Not according to public record, sir.
根据官方记录 没有 主人
Bring up the thermogenic signatures again.
把生热特征再拿过来
Factor in 3,000 degrees.
把3000度作为因素计入统计
The Oracle cloud has completed analysis.
神云已完成运算
Accessing satellites
跟卫星连接
and plotting the last 12 months of thermogenic occurrences now.
生成最近12个月的生热记录
Take away everywhere that there's been a Mandarin attack.
把满大人袭击过的地方都剔除
Nope.
不对
That. Are you sure that's not one of his?
那个 你确定那个不是他的?
It predates any known Mandarin attack.
它发生在任何已知的满大人袭击之前
The incident was the use of a bomb to assist a suicide.
是一起使用炸弹自杀的事件
Bring her around.
调近点
The heat signature is remarkably similar.
热度特征相当近似
3,000 degree Celsius.
3000摄氏度
That's two military guys.
是两个军人
Ever been to Tennessee, Jarvis?
去过田纳西州吗 贾维斯?
Creating a flight plan for Tennessee.
飞往田纳西州的航行规划中
Are we still at ding-dong?
还有人能来敲门吗?
We're supposed to be on total...
我们本该处于完全的...
security lockdown.
安全封锁之中
Come on, I threatened a terrorist. Who is that?
我刚威胁了一个恐怖分子 谁在敲门?
There's only so much I can do, sir,
我也只能做这么多了 主人
when you give the world's press your home address.
谁叫你告诉了全世界自己的住址
Right there is fine.
站那儿就行了
You're not the Mandarin.
你不是满大人
Are you? Are you?
你是吗? 是吗?
You don't remember.
你不记得了
Why am I not surprised?
果然不出我所料啊
Don't take it personally. I don't remember what I had for breakfast.
你别在意哦 我连今天早饭吃什么都忘了
Gluten-free waffles, sir.
无谷华夫饼 主人
That's right.
哦 是哦
Okay, look, I need to be alone with you, someplace not here.
好吧 我需要跟你单独谈谈 这里不行
It's urgent.
事情紧急
Normally, I'd go for that sort of thing, but now I'm in a committed relationship.
以前的话 我肯定没意见 但现在我有正式女朋友了
It's...
这...
- With her.  - Tony?
- 就是她的  - 托尼?
- Is somebody there?  - Yeah, it's Maya Hansen.
- 有人来了?  - 是的 玛雅・汉森
Old botanist pal
植物学界
that I used to know, barely.
的一个朋友 不太熟
Please don't tell me there's a 12-year-old kid
千万别告诉我 我有个从来没见过的12岁的孩子
waiting in the car that I've never met.
就坐在外面的车里等我
He's 13.
他已经13了
No, I need your help.
没有 但我需要你帮助
But, what for? Why now?
帮什么? 为什么要现在?
Because I read the papers, and frankly, I don't think you'll last the week.
因为我今天看了报纸 而且我觉得 你活不到周末了
I'll be fine.
我不会有事的
I'm sorry, with Happy in the hospital, I didn't know we were expecting guests.
对不起啊 哈皮住院了 我还以为不会有客人了呢
- We weren't.  - And old girlfriends.
- 的确很意外  - 还是前女友
- She's not, really.  - No, not really.
- 看起来不是  - 不是这样的
- It was just one night.  - Yep.
- 只是一夜情  - 是的
That's how you did it, isn't it?
的确是你的风格啊 是吧?
- It was a great night.  - Yep. Well, you know.
- 激情的一夜  - 这样说起来
- You saved yourself a world of pain.  - What?
- 你真是躲过这混球了啊  - 什么?
- I'm sure...  - Trust me. We're going out of town.
- 我确定...  - 相信我 我们马上离开这里
Okay. We've been through this.
哎 我们不是都说好了吗
- Nope.  - Yep!
- 不走  - 走!
- The man says no...  - Immediately and indefinitely.
- 男人说不...  - 立刻马上闪人
- Honey...  - Great idea. Let's go.
- 亲爱的...  - 好主意 我们这就走
I'm sorry, that's a terrible idea. Please don't touch her bags.
好不意思了 这不可能 别动她的包
This is how normal people behave.
其实正常人都是这样的
I can't protect you out there.
你出去了 我就保护不了你了
Is... Is that normal?
这... 这个是常规尺寸吗?
- Sadly, that is...  - Yes, this is normal!
- 不算太正常...  - 那非常正常
It's a big bunny. Relax about it!
不就是个大兔子吗 淡定点!
Calm down.
别激动
斯塔克发出威胁
- I got this for you.  - I'm aware of that.
- 这是我买给你的  - 我知道啊
斯塔克发出威胁
- I got this for you.  - I'm aware of that.
- 这是我买给你的  - 我知道啊
斯塔克发出威胁
- I got this for you.  - I'm aware of that.
- 这是我买给你的  - 我知道啊
斯塔克发出威胁
- I got this for you.  - I'm aware of that.
- 这是我买给你的  - 我知道啊
You still haven't even told me you liked it.
你都没告诉我 你喜不喜欢它
I don't like it.
我不喜欢的
I asked you three... You don't like it?
我都问你三次了... 原来你不喜欢?
- We are leaving the house.  - Guys?
- 我们得离开这里  - 话说?
That's not even up for discussion.
这事情还没完呢
- Can we...  - I said no. What?
- 我们就...  - 我说了不行 干嘛?
Do we need to worry about that?
这情况要紧吗?
I got you.
我来帮你了
I got you first.
我先保护住你的
Like I said, we can't stay here.
我就说吧 这里不能待了
Move! I'm right behind you.
快走! 我就跟着出来
Get her. I'm gonna find a way around.
去救她 我自有办法
Stop stopping. Get her. Get outside.
别傻着了啊 快去救她 快点出去
Go!
快走!
Oh, my God. Tony!
我的天啊 托尼!
Sir, Ms Potts is clear of the structure.
主人 波茨小姐已经逃离此建筑
Jarvis, where's my flight power?
贾维斯 我推进能量去哪里了?
Working on it, sir. This is a prototype.
正在安装 主人 这毕竟是台实验机
系统故障 脱机
That's one.
搞定一个
系统故障 脱机
That's one.
搞定一个
系统故障 脱机
That's one.
搞定一个
系统故障 脱机
That's one.
搞定一个
Sir, the suit is not combat ready.
主人 这盔甲还不适应战斗状态
That's two.
这是第二个
Tony!
托尼!
Sir, take a deep breath.
主人 请深呼吸
Flight power restored.
推进能源装配完成
Sir?
主人?
Sir!
主人!
All right, kill the alarm. I got it.
知道了把警报解除吧 我没事了
That's the emergency alert triggered by the power dropping below 5%.
这是能源不足5%的自动紧急警报
It's snowing, right? Where are we, upstate?
这是雪吧? 我们到哪里啦 北部了?
We are five miles outside of Rose Hill, Tennessee.
我们正在田纳西州玫瑰山外5公里的位置
Why?
怎么回事?
Jarvis. Not my idea.
贾维斯 我可没这么安排啊
What are we doing here? This is thousands of miles away!
我们来这地方干嘛? 这可牛头不对马嘴了
I gotta get Pepper, I got
我要去找佩珀 我要...
I prepared a flight plan. This was the location.
我计划了这次飞行 这就是目的地
Who asked you?
谁让你计划的?
Open the suit.
打开盔甲
I... I think I may be malfunctioning, sir.
我... 我出了点故障 主人
Open it, J.
快点打开 贾维斯
That's brisk.
一身轻松啊
Maybe I'll just cosy back up for a...
我还是缩回去好些...
I actually think I need to sleep now, sir.
我想我需要睡觉了 主人
Jarvis.
贾维斯
Jarvis?
贾维斯 你还在吗?
Don't leave me, buddy.
别不管我啊 伙计
Stark secure server now transferring to all known receivers.
斯塔克安保服务器 发送至所有已知接收器
Pepper, it's me.
佩珀 是我
I've got a lot of apologies to make and not a lot of time.
我知道我欠你很多对不起 但现在时间有限
So... First off, I'm so sorry I put you in harm's way.
所以... 首先 对不起我让你身处险境
That was selfish and stupid, and it won't happen again.
完全的自私加愚蠢 我保证不会发生了
Also, it's Christmastime and the rabbit's too big.
还有 圣诞快乐 那兔子的确太大只了
Done. Sorry.
就这些了 对不起
And I'm sorry in advance
还有 我提前道歉
because I can't come home yet.
因为我不可能准时回家了
I need to find this guy.
我要把那家伙挖出来
You gotta stay safe, that's all I know.
我只要你安全
I just stole a poncho from a wooden Indian.
我还刚从木头人身上偷了件斗篷
Let's get you comfy.
让你坐的舒服点
You happy now?
这下开心了吧?
Freeze!
站住!
Don't move.
别动
You got me.
你抓到我了
Nice potato gun.
土豆枪不错啊
Barrel's a little long.
枪管略长
Between that and the wide gauge, it's gonna diminish your FPS.
这种长度宽度的话 瞄起来可不准啊
And now you're out of ammo.
这样你就没子弹了
What's that thing on your chest?
你胸口上什么东西啊?
It's an electromagnet.
这是个电磁铁
You should know, you got a box of them right here.
你肯定知道 你这边一大把这种东西
What does it power?
用来干嘛的?
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
That...
那...
That's... Is that Iron Man?
那是... 那是钢铁侠吗?
Technically, I am.
严格的来说 我才是
Technically, you're dead.
严格的来说 你已经死了
满大人发动袭击 传斯塔克已死
Valid point.
好的吧
What happened to him?
他怎么了?
Life.
活着
I built him. I take care of him.
我造就了他 保养他
I'll fix him.
我会修好他的
Like a mechanic?
那不就是机械工吗?
Yeah.
算是吧
If I was building Iron Man and War Machine...
如果是我造钢铁侠和战争机器的话...
It's "Iron Patriot" now.
现在叫 钢铁爱国者号
That's way cooler.
这更酷了
No, it's not.
没有 完全没有
Anyways, I would have added in the retro...
不管怎么说 我会安装一个镜面...
- Retro-reflective panels?  - To make him stealth mode.
- 镜面反射装置?  - 让他可以隐形
- You want a stealth mode?  - Cool, right?
- 你是要隐形模式?  - 主意不错吧?
That's actually a good idea. Maybe I'll build one.
这想法不错 以后我可能会造一个
- Not a good idea.  - Oops.
- 别这样  - 啊哦
What are you doing? You're gonna break his finger?
看你干了什么? 你是要掰断他手指吗?
He's in pain. He's been injured. Leave him alone.
他受伤了 浑身酸痛着呢 离他远点
Sorry.
对不起
Are you?
你真心的吗?
Don't worry about it, I'll fix it.
别担心 我来解决好了
So, who's home?
谁在家呢?
My mom already left for the diner, and Dad went to 7-11 to get scratchers.
我妈去餐厅上班了 我爸去7-11点买刮刮乐了
I guess he won, because that was six years ago.
我猜他应该是中奖了 因为他一去就是六年了
Which happens. Dads leave. No need to be a pussy about it.
这时有发生 爸爸离开孩子 没什么好在意的
Here's what I need.
我需要以下这些东西
A laptop, a digital watch, a cell phone,
一台笔记本 一只电子手表 一部手机
the pneumatic actuator from your bazooka over there,
你那边小钢炮上的气旋螺纹管
a map of town, a big spring and a tuna fish sandwich.
本镇的地图 大弹簧和一个金枪鱼三明治
What's in it for me?
这么做 我有什么好处?
- Salvation. What's his name?  - Who?
- 拯救你 他叫什么名字?  - 谁?
The kid that bullies you at school. What's his name?
在学校欺负你的那个人 他叫什么名字?
How'd you know that?
你怎么知道的?
I got just the thing.
我这个东西刚好对你胃口
This is a pinata for a cricket.
这是装蟋蟀的小罐子
I'm kidding. This is a very powerful weapon.
开玩笑的 这是件十分厉害的武器
Point it away from your face, press the button on top,
别对着自己的脸 按下顶部的按钮
it discourages bullying.
就能把别人吓跑
Non-lethal, just to cover one's ass. Deal?
无性命之忧 正好为防身之用 如何?
Deal? What do you say?
怎么样?
- Deal?  - Deal.
- 成交吗?  - 成交
What's your name?
你叫什么?
Harley. And you're...
哈利 你叫...
The mechanic.
机械工
Tony.
托尼
You know what keeps going through my head?
你知道我脑子在念什么吗?
"Where's my sandwich?"
我的三明治呢?
Where is Tony Stark?
托尼・斯塔克在哪里?
Stark secure server. Retinal scan verified.
塔克安保服务器 身份验证成功
Pepper, it's me.
佩珀 是我
I've got a lot of apologies to make and not a lot of time.
我知道我欠你很多对不起 但现在时间有限
So... First off, I'm so sorry I put you in harm's way.
所以... 首先 对不起我让你身处险境
That was selfish and stupid and it won't happen again.
完全的自私加愚蠢 我保证不会发生了
Why were you at the house tonight?
你今天为什么来我家?
What was so important that you had to speak to Tony?
你到底有什么要紧的事要跟托尼讲?
I think that my boss is working for the Mandarin.
我怀疑我老板在为满大人工作
So, if you still want to talk about it
如果你还想知道的话
I suggest that we get ourselves someplace safe.
我建议 我们找个安全的地方
Your boss works for the Mandarin, you think?
你老板在为满大人工作?
But Tony says you're a botanist. So...
但托尼说你是个植物学家...
That figures. What I actually am is a biological DNA coder
可以那么说 我实际上是DNA基因编码师
running a team of 40 out of a privately funded think tank.
有个四十人的团队 是一个私人智囊团的分支
But sure, you can call me a botanist.
当然你也可以说 我是个植物学家
This boss of yours, does he have a name?
你的老板叫什么名字?
Yeah, Aldrich Killian.
阿尔德里奇・基利安
We took the house down, Sir. But there's no sign of a body.
长官 房子被我们炸毁了 但没有发现任何尸体
- I see.  - No Stark.
- 了解  - 未发现斯塔克
I have to go.
我要走了
The master is about to record and he's a little...
大师应该要录像了 但他有点...
Well, you know how he gets.
你知道他的脾气
Keep your appointment tonight and call me when it's done.
今天继续按计划进行 完事了再打给我
All right, everybody. No talking and no eye contact.
都给我听着 不许说话 也不许眼神交流
Unless you want to get shot in the face.
不然直接一枪爆头
Report in.
报告
Path is clear.
入口安全
The master is travelling.
大师进去了
Well, then, what are we waiting for?
好了吧 我们还在等什么呢?
The sandwich was fair, the spring was a little rusty,
三明治还行 就是弹簧有点锈
the rest of the materials, I'll make do.
其他的材料 先凑合着吧
By the way, when you said your sister had a watch...
另外 你说会给我你妹妹的表
- Yeah?  - l was kind of hoping
- 怎么了?  - 我还以为
for something a little more adult than that.
是稍微比这个成熟一点的表
She's six. Anyway, it's a limited edition.
她才六岁 拜托 这可是限量版
When can we talk about New York?
什么时候我们说说纽约事件吧?
Maybe never. Relax about it.
估计不会说了 忘了吧
What about the Avengers? Can we talk about them?
那复仇者联盟呢? 我们能说他们吗?
I dunno. Later. Hey, kid, give me a little space.
算了 晚点再说吧 小鬼 给点私人空间哦
What's the official story here? What happened?
这边是什么个情况? 发生了什么事了?
I guess this guy named Chad Davis used to live roundabouts.
有个叫查德・戴维斯的人 就住在这街角
He won a bunch of medals in the army.
他参军的时候 赢了很多奖章
And one day, folks said he went crazy and made, you know, a bomb.
后来大伙说他突然疯了 他做了个炸弹
Then he blew himself up, right here.
就在这里 把自己炸飞了
- Six people died, right?  - Yeah.
- 死了六个人 是吧?  - 是的
- Including Chad Davis.  - Yeah, yeah.
- 算上查德・戴维斯  - 没错
Yeah. That doesn't make sense.
真的吗 这没道理啊
Think about it.
想想看
Six dead. Only five shadows.
死了六个 但阴影只有五个
Yeah.
是啊
People said these shadows are like the marks of souls going to heaven.
人们说 这些影子是灵魂进入天堂的印记
Except the bomb guy.
那炸弹哥就可怜了
He went to hell, on account of he didn't get a shadow.
他落入了地狱 所以他的影子也随他进去了
That's why there's only five.
所以才只有五个影子
- Do you buy that?  - It's what everyone says.
- 你相信吗?  - 大家都这么说
You know what this crater reminds me of?
你知道这坑让我想到什么了吗?
No idea. I'm not... I don't care.
不知道 我也不... 不关心
That giant Wormhole in New York.
纽约的那个巨大虫洞
Does it remind you?
它让你想起什么?
That's manipulative. I don't want to talk about it.
想套我的话 我不想说
Are they coming back? The aliens?
外星人? 它们会回来吗?
Maybe. Can you stop?
有可能 你能闭嘴吗?
Remember what I told you, that I have an anxiety issue?
我不是跟你说过 我有焦虑症吗?
Does this subject make you... edgy?
这话题让你... 不淡定了吗?
Yeah, a little bit. Can I just catch my breath for a second?
是有一点 我能喘口气了吗?
Are there bad guys in Rose Hill?
玫瑰山有坏人吗?
Do you need a plastic bag to breathe into?
你需要个袋子帮你呼吸吗?
- Do you have medication?  - No.
- 你吃药了吗?  - 没有
- Do you need to be on it?  - Probably.
- 你需要吃药吗?  - 有可能
- Do you have PTSD?  - I don't think so.
- 你有创伤后遗症吗?  - 我不觉得
Are you... are you going completely mental?
你会... 你会变成精神病吗?
I can stop. Do you want me to stop?
我可以闭嘴 你要我闭嘴吗?
Remember when I said to stop doing that?
我不是早让你闭嘴吗?
I swear that you're gonna freak me out.
我发誓 你快把我逼疯了
Man, you did it, didn't you? You happy now?
熊孩子 你还真把我逼疯了 你开心了吧?
What did I say?
我说了什么啊?
Hey! Wait up!
嘿! 等等我!
Wait, wait.
等等 等等
What the hell was that?
你怎么了?
Your fault. You spazzed me out.
你害我抽抽了
Okay, back to business. Where were we?
好了 正经事 我们说到哪里了?
The guy who died.
那人死了
Relatives? Mom? Mrs Davis, where is she?
他家属呢? 母亲? 戴维斯女士 她在哪里?
Where she always is.
她呆就一个地方
See? Now, you're being helpful.
看到没? 这才帮到点子上了
Sorry.
对不起
Lady?
女士?
Is this...
这是...
Thank you.
谢谢
Nice haircut. it suits you.
头发不错啊 很衬你
Nice watch.
手表不错啊
Yeah. A limited edition.
是啊 还是限量款哦
I don't doubt it.
那必须的
Well, have a good evening.
晚上玩的开心啊
Mrs Davis?
戴维斯女士?
Mind if I join you?
我能坐下吗?
Free country.
人生自由
Sure is.
的确如此
All right.
好吧
Where would you like to start?
有话快说吧?
I just want to say, I'm sorry about your loss.
我想说 我为你晚年丧子感到很难过
I want to know what you think happened.
我想了解 到底发生了什么
Look, I brought your damn file. You take it, go.
这资料我给你带来了 你拿上走人吧
Whatever was in here, he wanted no part of it.
不管里面怎么说 都不是他想做的
Clearly, you're waiting for someone else. Huh?
显然的 你在等其他人 对吧?
Supposed to meet someone here?
有人会在这里和你碰头?
Yeah.
是的
Mrs Davis, your son didn't kill himself.
戴维斯女士 你儿子没有自杀
I guarantee you, he didn't kill anyone.
我向你保证 他没有伤害任何人
Someone used him.
是有人利用了他
What?
什么?
As a weapon.
有人把他当枪使
You're not the person that called me after all, are you?
你不是那个电话里的人 是吧?
Actually, I am.
其实 我才是
Hey, hey, hey! What's all this about? What the hell is going on here?
嘿 嘿! 这怎么回事? 这边什么情况?
It's called an arrest.
我这是在抓人
- Sheriff, is it?  - Yes, ma'am, it is. And you are?
- 警长 对吧?  - 是的 女士 你是?
Homeland Security. We good here?
国土安全局 没问题了吧?
No, we're not "good."
问题还是有的
I need a little more information than that.
我可需要知道更多的消息
I think it's a little above your pay grade, Sheriff.
我说这事还轮不到你来管 警长
Yeah? Why don't you get on the horn to Nashville, and upgrade me?
是吗? 那你要不在州政府打点一下 让我升个官?
All right. You know what? I was hoping to do this the smart way
好吧 怎么说呢? 我本来还打算简单通融一下就好了
but the fun way is always good.
不过大家开心一下也不错啊
Deputy, get this woman out of...
副警长 逮捕这女的...
Hey, hot wings, you want to party? Come on, you and me, let's go.
嘿 辣妹 你想玩? 快点 我和你好好玩玩 走吧
- Crazy, huh?  - Yep.
- 简直疯了 是吧?  - 说得对
Watch this.
看我的
You walked right into this one. I've dated hotter chicks than you.
你穿火而入不算什么 我泡过更火辣的妞
That's all you got?
你就这点本事吗?
A cheap trick and a cheesy one-liner?
就凭一个便宜的把戏和一句俏皮话吗?
Sweetheart, that could be the name of my autobiography.
甜心 这句话都可以做我自传的书名了
- Let me go!  - Help me!
- 放开我!  - 救命!
Anyway...
不管怎么说...
Hey, kid, what would you like for Christmas?
小子 圣诞节想要什么礼物?
Mr Stark, I am so sorry.
斯塔克先生 对不起
No, no, no. I think he was trying to say,
不对 不对 我猜他想说的是
"I want my goddamn file."
"我他妈的想要我的文件"
It's not your fault, kid.
不是你的错 孩子
Remember what I told you about bullies?
还记得我跟你说过 别人欺负你该怎么办吗?
You like that, Westworld?
喜欢这招吗 未来人?
That's the thing about smart guys,
聪明人都有一个特点
we always cover our ass.
我们总是留一手
You're welcome.
不客气
For what? Did I miss something?
为什么? 我错过什么了吗?
Me, saving your life.
是我救了你的命
Yeah. A, I saved you first. B, thanks. Sort of.
没错 第一 我先救了你 第二 就算谢谢你吧
And C, if you do someone a solid, don't be a yutz.
第三 你要是想帮人家的忙 别搞得那么蠢
All right? Just play it cool. Otherwise you come off grandiose.
好吗? 潇洒一点 不然太做作了
Unlike you?
一点都不像你是吗?
Admit it, you need me.
承认吧 你需要我
We're connected.
我们懂彼此
What I need is for you to go home, be with your mom,
我需要你回家找你妈
keep your trap shut, guard the suit,
把嘴管严了 看好盔甲
and stay connected to the telephone,
别让电话占线了
because if I call, you better pick up. Okay?
因为我打来的时候 你最好能接到 好吗?
Can you feel that? We're done here.
明白了吗? 这里的事搞定了
Move out of the way, or I'm gonna run you over.
别挡道 不然我会把你撞倒的
Bye, kid.
再见
I'm sorry, kid.
对不起 孩子
You did good.
你干得不错
So, now you're just gonna leave me here, like my dad?
你现在要像我爸爸那样把我丢在这吗?
Yeah.
没错
Wait, you're guilt-tripping me, aren't you?
等等 你想让我内疚是吧?
I'm cold.
我好冷
I can tell. You know how I can tell?
我看出来了 你知道我怎么看出来的吗?
Because we're connected.
因为我们懂彼此
It was worth a shot.
试试也无妨
You get this. It's affordable. It's gorgeous.
你买了它 价格适宜又美观
It goes with any decor...
可以跟各种装饰搭配...
- What happened to picture?  - Go to override.
- 画面是怎么了?  - 进行画面覆盖
- How is this happening again?  - Fine. Override to Los Angeles.
- 怎么又来了?  - 好吧 把画面接到洛杉矶
I'm trying. There's nothing I can...
我正在尝试 但我什么也...
Well, where is the feed coming from?
信号从哪来?
I don't know, it's in all of our receivers and I...
不知道 接收器收到的都是这个信号 我...
The entire East Coast, the satellites are down.
整个东海岸的卫星都失控了
It's not just our station.
不只是我们的接收站
What about a backup manual?
试试启动备用手控?
We have an unauthorised broadcast cutting through...
我们有一个未经授权的广播切进来...
Mr Vice President, I think you should see this.
副总统先生 我觉得您该看看这个
Oh, God, not again.
哦 不 又来了
Is the President getting this?
总统看到了吗?
Mr President.
总统先生
Only two lessons remain.
还要给你两个教训
And I intend to finish this before Christmas morning.
而我打算在圣诞节那天早晨完成
Meet Thomas Richards.
认识一下托马斯・理查德
Good strong name. Good strong job.
他有个好名声跟一个硬饭碗
Thomas, here, is an accountant for the Roxxon Oil Corporation.
这个托马斯是罗克森石油公司的会计
But I'm sure he's a really good guy.
但我确定他一定是个好人
I'm going to shoot him in the head,
我打算让他的脑袋开花
live on your television, in 30 seconds.
三十秒钟后现场直播
No!
不!
The number for this telephone is in your cell phone.
你手机上就有这个电话的号码
Exciting, isn't it, imagining how it got there?
很刺激是吧 在想这个号码是怎么到你手机上的吗?
America,
美国人民听着
if your president calls me in the next half-minute,
如果总统在半分钟之内打给我
Tom lives.
托马斯就能活
Go!
开始!
How did he hack my phone?
他怎么黑进我电话的?
We can't allow terrorists to dictate...
我们不能受恐怖分子的控制...
I have to make this call.
我必须打这个电话
I'd strongly advise against that.
我强烈建议您不要这么做
This is the right thing to do.
这么做才是对的
There's just one lesson left, President Ellis.
还剩一个教训了 埃利斯总统
So run away, hide, kiss your children goodbye.
赶快逃吧 藏起来 跟你的孩子吻别
Because nothing,
因为没有人能救你
not your army, not your red, white and blue attack dog,
你的军队救不了你 你那穿红白蓝条纹的警犬
can save you.
也救不了你
I'll see you soon.
我们很快会再见的
Tell Rhodes, find this lunatic right now.
通知罗迪 让他赶快找到这个疯子
Sir, we tracked the broadcast signal.
先生 我们追踪到了广播信号
We have a possible point of origin in Pakistan
我们在巴基斯坦找到了可能的目标点
and the Patriot is ready to strike.
"爱国者"已经准备出击
- Right now.  - Yes, sir.
- 开始吧  - 是 先生
Man. Happy, Happy, Happy...
老天 哈皮 哈皮...
Don't move!
别动!
Hang on a second.
等一下
Hello?
你好?
You ever have a chick straddling you, and you look up
你碰没碰到过一个妞正坐在你身上 你抬头看时
and suddenly she's glowing from the inside out, kind of a bright orange?
她突然间从里到外的散发出一种亮橙色的光
Yeah, I've had that. Who is this?
嗯 我碰到过 你谁啊?
It's me, pal.
是我 哥们
Now, last time I went missing, if I remember correctly,
话说我没记错的话 上次我失踪的时候
you came looking for me. What are you doing?
你还去找我了 你干嘛呢?
A little knock-and-talk, making friends in Pakistan.
在巴基斯坦小小的查访一下 交交朋友
What are you doing?
你干嘛呢?
Your redesign, your big rebrand, that was AIM, right?
你那套盔甲的重新设计是AIM公司做的吧?
Yeah.
是啊
I'm gonna find a heavy-duty comm sat now, I need your login.
我现在去找一个大型的通信卫星 我需要你的账号
It's the same as it's always been, "WarMachine68."
一直都是"战争机器68号"
And password, please.
还有密码 谢谢
Look, I gotta change it every time you hack in, Tony.
听着 托尼 你每次黑进来我都得改密码
It's not the 80s, nobody says "hack" any more.
这不是80年代了 没人再说"黑进来"了
Give me your login.
密码给我
"WAR MACHINE ROX" with an "X," all caps.
"战争机器火箭号" 火箭号以"X"结尾 全部大写
Yeah, okay.
你就尽管笑吧
That is so much better than "Iron Patriot."
这可比"钢铁爱国者"强多了
Very nice. Very nice.
非常好 非常好
I have one question for you.
我有一个问题要问你
What would you like for Christmas this year?
这个圣诞节你想要什么礼物?
Well, David...
大卫 我告诉你...
Do not erase a programme from my DVR unless you are 100% sure...
除非你100%的确定 不然别删我硬盘录像机上的节目...
One more time! Ms Elk Ridge, everybody! All right.
再来一次! 让我们感谢艾克・瑞德! 好的
Because you erase my shows!
因为你删了我的演出!
连接速度慢
That ain't gonna cut it.
网速不行
We talked about this.
我们谈过这个了
Excuse me, sir. I don't know who...
抱歉 先生 我不知道谁...
Mom, I need to call you back. Something magical is happening.
妈 我一会再打给你 见证奇迹的时刻到了
- Tony Stark is in my van.  - Keep it down.
- 托尼・斯塔克在我车里  - 小点儿声
- Tony Stark is in my van!  - No, he's not.
- 托尼・斯塔克就在我车里!  - 不 他不在
I knew you were still alive!
我就知道你还活着!
Come on in. Close the door.
进来 把门关上
Wow. Can I just say, sir...
哇哦 先生 我能说...
Yep.
说吧
I am your biggest fan.
我是你的铁粉
First, is this your van? Is anyone else gonna come in?
第一 这是你的车吗? 会有别人进来吗?
No, no, no. Just us.
不 不 不 就我们俩
Great. What's your name?
很好 你叫什么名字?
- Gary.  - Gary.
- 我叫盖瑞  - 你好 盖瑞
- Wow.  - Right there is fine.
- 哇哦  - 这样就行了
- Okay.  - Okay?
- 行  - 行吗?
I get a lot of this, it's okay.
我经常遇到这种情况 没关系的
- Good. Can I just say?  - What do you want? Yeah.
- 好 我能说?  - 你想说啥? 说
I don't know if you can tell,
我不知道你能不能看出来
but I have patterned my whole look after you.
但我完全是照着你的形象打扮自己的
- My hair's a little...  - it's fine.
- 我的头发有点...  - 没关系
It's not right, 'cause there's no product in it.
头发不像 因为我没用护发素
Right.
这样啊
I don't want to make things awkward for you, but I do have to show you...
我不想让你觉得尴尬 但我必须给你看...
Boom!
轰!
A Hispanic Scott Baio.
是西班牙那个斯克特・拜奥吧
- I'm sorry. Is that me?  - Yeah. It's... I mean...
- 对不起 是我吗?  - 是 它有点... 我是说...
I had them do it off a doll that I made, so it's not like it's off a picture.
我让他们照着我做的一个人偶纹的 所以不像照着图片纹得那么逼真
- So it's a little bit...  - Gary. Listen to me, okay?
- 所以它有点...  - 盖瑞 听我说 好吗?
I don't want to clip your wings, here. We're both a little over-excited.
我不想打消你的热情 我们都有点过度兴奋了
I got an issue. I'm chasing bad guys.
我遇到麻烦了 我在追查坏蛋
I'm trying to grab a little something from some hard-crypt data files.
我在试着从大反派的资料档中找点东西
I don't have enough juice.
但我网速不够
I need you to jump on the roof... right?
我需要你爬到车顶上... 好吗?
Recalibrate the ISDNs.
重新调整一下综合业务数字网
Pump it up by about 40%.
把网速提高40%
- Got it.  - All right? It's a mission.
- 明白  - 没问题吧? 这是项任务
Yeah.
好的
Tony needs Gary.
托尼需要盖瑞
And Gary needs Tony.
盖瑞也需要托尼
- Be quiet about it. Go.  - Yeah.
- 悄悄地 去吧  - 好
What would you regard as the defining moment of your life?
你觉得你人生的决定性时刻是什么时候?
I think that would be the day I decided not to let my injury beat me.
我认为是我决定不再让我的伤打败我的时候
Will you please state your name for the camera?
请对着镜头说出你的名字?
Ellen Brandt.
我叫爱伦・布兰德
Okay. So, the injections are administered periodically.
好 我们会定期地进行注射
Addiction will not be tolerated.
不允许上瘾
Those who cannot regulate will be out from the programme.
那些不能控制自己的人将被驱逐出计划
Once misfits, cripples...
曾经不适合社会的那些人 还有残疾人...
You are the next iteration of human evolution.
你们是人类进化史的下一个篇章
Everybody, before we start...
朋友们 在我们开始之前...
I promise you, looking back at your life, there will be nothing as bitter
我向你们保证 今天你深思熟虑后决定光荣地早一步承担风险
as the memory of that glorious risk you prudently elected to forego.
当你回首你的一生 再不会有这么痛苦的回忆
Today is your glory...
今天是你们的光荣日...
Let's begin.
我们开始吧
We gotta get out of here! We gotta get out of here!
我们得离开这! 我们得离开这!
Get her out! Get them out of here!
把她带出去! 把他们带出去!
A bomb is not a bomb when it's a misfire.
原来不是炸弹 而是走火
The stuff doesn't always work. Right, pal?
那东西也有不好使的时候 是吧 哥们?
It's faulty, but you found a buyer, didn't you?
虽然有缺陷 但你还是找到了买主 是吧?
Sold it to the Mandarin.
卖给了满大人
Got you, pal.
抓到你了 哥们
What happened?
出什么事了?
Fun fact.
有趣的是
Before he built rockets for the Nazis,
在给纳粹造火箭之前
the idealistic Wernher Von Braun
这个理想主义版的韦纳・冯・布劳恩
dreamed of space travel.
梦想太空旅行
He stargazed.
他眺望着星空
Do you know what he said when the first V-2 hit London?
当第一个V-2导弹袭击伦敦的时候你知道他说什么吗?
"The rocket performed perfectly."
"火箭运行得很完美"
"It just landed on the wrong planet."
"只是降落在了错误的星球"
See, we all begin wide-eyed. Pure science.
你看 我们刚开始都很天真 纯搞科学
And then the ego steps in, the obsession.
然后自负情绪就出现了 接着是痴迷
And you look up,
你再抬头看时
you're a long way from shore.
已经远远地偏离了初衷
You can't be too hard on yourself, Maya.
对自己别太苛刻了 玛雅
I mean, you gave your research to a think tank.
我是说 你把你的研究给了智囊团
Yeah, but Killian built that think tank on military contracts.
是 但基利安是基于军事合同建立的智囊团
That's exactly what we used to do.
我们过去就是那样
So, don't judge yourself.
所以别责怪自己
Thank you, Pepper.
谢谢你 佩珀
I really appreciate that.
我真的很感激你说的这番话
- Hi, good evening. Come on in.  - Good evening.
- 嗨 晚上好 请进  - 晚上好
Maya, run!
玛雅 快跑!
Hi, Pepper.
你好 佩珀
So, you want to tell me why you were at Stark's mansion last night?
你想告诉我昨晚你为什么会在斯塔克家里吗?
I'm trying to fix this thing.
我在努力挽局面
I didn't know you and the master were gonna blow the place up.
我不知道你跟大师要炸掉他家
I see. So, you were trying to save Stark, when he threatened us?
我明白了 就是说斯塔克威胁了我们 你还要去救他?
I've told you, Killian, we can use him.
我告诉过你 基利安 我们可以利用他
Pepper. Pepper. Pepper.
佩珀 放手 放手
Look, if we want to launch product next year, I need Stark.
看 如果我们想明年投放这个商品 我就需要斯塔克
He just lacked a decent incentive. Now, he has one.
他只是缺少点像样的动力 现在他有了
This is support team Blue-Zero.
这是支援小队蓝零队
Sending coordinates for a suspected Mandarin broadcast point of origin.
正在发送一个可疑的满大人发信坐标
Copy...
收到...
Nobody move.
不许动
Support Blue-Zero,
支援小队蓝零队
unless the Mandarin's next attack on the U.S.
除非满大人对美国进行的的下一个攻击
involves cheaply-made sportswear,
跟粗制滥造的运动服有关
I think you messed up again.
不然我觉得你们又搞错了
Yes, you're free, if you weren't before.
是 你们自由了 如果你们之前不自由的话
It's... Of course.
这... 当然
Yes, ma'am.
是的 女士
Iron Patriot on the job.
这是"钢铁爱国者"的职责
Happy to help.
很高兴能帮忙
No need to thank me, ma'am.
不用感谢我 女士
It's my pleasure.
这是我的荣幸
Savin? I've acquired the Patriot armour.
赛文吗? 我已经把"爱国者"的盔甲弄到手了
If you want this suit,
如果你想要这个盔甲
you're going to have to pry my cold dead body out of it.
你得把我冰冷的尸体从里面撬出来
That's the plan, Colonel.
我就是这么想的 上校
Harley, tell me what's happening. Give me a full report.
哈利 告诉我情况怎么样 给我全面地报告一下
Yeah, I'm still eating that candy. Do you want me to keep eating it?
好 我正在吃糖 你觉得我该继续吃吗?
- How much have you had?  - Two or three bowls.
- 你已经吃多少了?  - 两三碗了吧
- Can you still see straight?  - Sort of.
- 你看东西清楚吗?  - 还行吧
That means you're fine. Give me Jarvis.
那你就没事 把电话给贾维斯
Jarvis, how are we?
贾维斯 情况怎么样?
It's totally fine, sir. I seem to do quite well for a stretch,
完全没问题 我这段时间还挺好的
and then at the end of the sentence, I say the wrong cranberry.
但是在句末 我总是说错话
And, sir, you were right.
还有 主人 你是对的
Once I factored in available AIM downlink facilities
我每次进入AIM公司的下载链接设施
I was able to pinpoint the Mandarin's broadcast signal.
都能找到满大人的广播信号
What are we talking? Far East, Europe, North Africa...
是哪里啊? 远东 欧洲 北非...
Iran, Pakistan, Syria? Where is it?
伊朗 巴基斯坦 还是叙利亚? 到底在哪?
Actually, sir, it's in Miami.
事实上是在迈阿密 主人
Okay, kid, I'm gonna have to walk you through
好 孩子 我会一步步教你
rebooting Jarvis's speech drive,
重新启动贾维斯的语音驱动
but not right now.
但不是现在
Harley, where is he really?
哈利 它到底在哪?
Just look on the screen and tell me where it is.
看看屏幕 告诉我在哪
It does say Miami, Florida.
上面确实写着弗洛里达州的迈阿密
Okay, first things first, I need the armour. Where are we at with it?
好 重中之重 我需要我的盔甲 它现在情况怎么样?
It's not charging.
它充不上电
Actually, sir, it is charging, but the power source is questionable.
主人 其实在充电 只是电源有点问题
It may not succeed in revitalising the Mark 42.
可能没办法重新激活42号
What's questionable about electricity? All right?
电力有什么问题? 还好吗?
It's my suit, and I can't... I'm not gonna? I don't wanna...
那是我的盔甲 我不能... 我不会... 我不想...
Oh, God, not again.
天啊 又来了
Tony?
托尼?
Are you having another attack?
你又发作了吗?
I didn't even mention New York.
我都没提纽约
Right, and then you just said it by name while denying having said it.
行了 你说你没说的时候就把它的名字说出来了
Okay...
好吧...
God, what am I gonna do?
天啊 我该怎么办?
Just breathe. Really, just breathe.
呼吸 听我的 呼吸
You're a mechanic, right?
你是个机械师 是吧?
Right.
是啊
You said so.
你说过
Yes, I did.
对 我是说过
Why don't you just build something?
那你为什么不造点东西?
Okay.
好吧
Thanks, kid.
谢谢你 孩子
弗洛里达州 迈阿密
Why is it so hot in here? I told you to put it at 68.
这里怎么这么热啊? 我告诉过你把温度调到68
My fault again.
我又错了
Let me tell you something, sweetheart. I am not your personal air con...
我告诉你 甜心 我不是你的私人空调控制...
Well.
哇哦
I wouldn't go in there for 20 minutes.
20分钟之内我不会进去
Now, which one of you is Vanessa?
你们当中谁是瓦妮莎?
That's me.
我是
Nessie.
妮莎
Did you know that fortune cookies aren't even Chinese?
你们知道幸运饼根本不是中国的发明吗?
There's some guy over here.
有个人藏在这里
They're made by Americans, based on a Japanese recipe.
那是美国人按照日本食谱做的
Hey!
嘿!
Bloody hell. Bloody hell.
惨了 惨了
Don't move.
别动
I'm not moving. You want something? Take it.
我没动 你想要什么? 就拿去
Although the guns are all fake
尽管这些枪都是假的
because those wankers wouldn't trust me with the real ones.
因为那些笨蛋不相信我能用好真家伙
- What?  - Hey, do you fancy either of the birds?
- 啥?  - 嘿 你喜欢这两个小妞吗?
Heard enough.
够了
You're not him. The Mandarin, the real guy.
你是替身吧 那个满大人 真人
Where?
在哪?
Where's the Mandarin? Where is he?
满大人在哪? 他在哪?
He's here. He's here, but he's not here.
他在这儿 可他又不在这儿
- He's here, but he's not here.  - What do you mean?
- 在这儿 但不在这儿  - 你什么意思?
It's complicated. Hey, it's complicated.
事情很复杂的 一言难尽
- It is.  - It's complicated.
- 快说  - 很复杂的
Uncomplicate it. Ladies, out.
给我解释 女士们 请出去
Get out of the bed. Get into the bathroom.
下床 去浴室
Sit.
坐着
Oh, Jesus.
老天
My name is Trevor. Trevor Slattery.
我叫特雷弗 全名特雷弗・斯莱特利
What are you?
你到底是什么?
A decoy? You're a double, right?
你是诱饵? 还是替身?
You mean like an understudy? No, absolutely not.
你以为我是替身? 我才不是
Don't hurt the face! I'm an actor.
别打脸! 我是个演员
You got a minute to live. Fill it with words.
给你一分钟时间说明
It's just a role. "The Mandarin," it's not real.
我只是演这个角色 "满大人"本身根本不存在
Then how did you get here, Trevor?
那你是怎么来的 特雷弗?
Well, I had a little problem with substances.
嗯 我有一次毒瘾犯了
And I ended up doing things, no two ways about it,
结果 我不得已地在街头
in the street, that a man shouldn't do.
犯了点事情
- Next?  - Then,
- 然后呢?  - 然后
they approached me about the role,
他们推荐我演这个角色
and they knew about the drugs.
他们知道我吸毒
What did they say? They'd get you off them?
他们怎么说? 帮你戒毒?
They said they'd give me more.
他们说会给我很多毒品
They gave me things.
他们给我很多东西
They gave me this palace. They gave me plastic surgery.
给我这座宫殿 还给我整容
They gave me things.
给了我不少东西
Did you just nod off?
你刚才睡着了?
Hey.
嘿
No, and a lovely speedboat.
不 还有那艘超酷的快艇
And the thing was, he needed someone
关键是 他想要找个人
to take credit for some accidental explosions.
为那几起意外爆炸事件背黑锅
"He"?
"他"?
- Killian?  - Killian.
- 是基利安?  - 就是他
- He created you?  - He created me.
- 他创造了你?  - 没错
Custom-made terror threat.
独具特色的恐怖袭击
Yes. Yes.
没错
His think tank thinked it up.
他的智囊团出的主意
The pathology of a serial killer.
掌握连环杀手的病理
The manipulation of Western iconography.
运用经典西方肖像学
Ready for another lesson?
准备好接受教训了吗?
Blah, blah, blah.
如此这般
No.
不
Of course, it was my performance that brought the Mandarin to life.
当然 是我的表演让这个满大人栩栩如生
Your performance?
你的表演?
Where people died?
会死人的表演?
No, they didn't.
不 那是假的
Look around you. The costumes, green screen.
看你周围 各种戏服 绿色屏障
Honestly, I wasn't on location for half this stuff.
说老实话 一半的时候我都不是在实地拍摄
And when I was, it was movie magic, love.
如果是 那也是电影的把戏
I'm sorry, but I got a best friend who's in a coma
抱歉 可是我有个好朋友因为你的缘故
and he might not wake up.
现在还昏迷不醒
So you're gonna have to answer for that.
我觉得你还是得为此负责
You're still going down, pal.
你还是有麻烦的
You under...
你知道...
Okay, Trevor, what did you tell him?
好吧 特雷弗 你和他说了些什么?
- I didn't tell him anything.  - Nothing?
- 我什么都没说  - 没说?
No.
没说
You should have pressed the panic button.
你该按下应急开关的
Well, I panicked, but then I handled it.
本来很"紧急" 可我控制住了
Okay.
好吧
It's just like old times, huh?
就像以前一样 是吧?
Yeah. With zip ties. It's a ball.
嗯 还玩上了捆绑游戏 很爽
It wasn't my idea.
这事并不是我的主意
Okay. So you took Killian's card.
嗯 但你接受了基利安的提议
I took his money.
我接受的是他的钱
And here you are 13 years later, in a dungeon.
13年以后 你还在这个地牢里
- No.  - Yeah.
- 不  - 就是
No, you're in a dungeon. I'm free to go.
你在地牢里 我随时都可以离开
Yeah?
是吗?
A lot has happened, Tony.
发生了很多事情 托尼
But I'm close.
但就快完成了
EXTREMIS is practically stabilised.
终极生物很稳定
I'm telling you it isn't. I'm on the street.
我和你说 这根本不稳定 我在街上看到的
People are going bang. They're painting the walls.
人们爆炸开来 鲜血把墙都涂满了
Maya, you're kidding yourself.
玛雅 你是在自欺欺人
Then help me fix it.
那帮我完善它
Did I do that?
这是我写的?
Yes.
是的
I remember the night, not the morning.
我只记得那晚 第二天的事情忘了
Is this what you've been chasing around?
你一生的理想就是这个吗?
- You don't remember?  - I can't help you.
- 你不记得了?  - 我帮不了你
You used to have a moral psychology.
你以前是富有正义感和道德的
You used to have ideals.
你以前充满理想
You wanted to help people.
乐于助人
Now look at you.
看看现在的你
I get to wake up every morning with someone who
我现在每天早晨醒来 发现陪伴我的她
still has their soul.
至少还有颗心
Get me out of here.
放我出去
Come on.
快点
You know what my old man used to say to me?
你知道我老爹以前说过什么?
One of his favourite of many sayings...
他挂在嘴边最多的就是...
"The early bird gets the worm, but the second mouse gets the cheese."
"早起鸟儿有虫吃 捕鼠器上奶酪总是第二只老鼠吃"
You're not still pissed off about the Switzerland thing, are you?
你不会还在为瑞士的那次耿耿于怀吧?
How can I be pissed at you, Tony?
我怎么可能生你的气呢 托尼?
I'm here to thank you.
我是来感谢你的
You gave me the greatest gift that anybody's ever given me.
你给予我别人从来送过的珍贵礼物
Desperation.
就是绝望
If you think back to Switzerland,
回忆起瑞士那次
you said you'd meet me on the rooftop, right?
你说你会来天台见我 对吧?
For the first 20 minutes,
开始20分钟的时候
I actually thought you'd show up.
我还天真地以为你会出现
And the next hour...
过了一个小时...
I considered taking that one-step shortcut to the lobby.
我曾想过直接从天台去一楼
If you know what I mean.
你懂我的意思吧
Honestly, I'm still trying to figure out what happened to the first mouse.
老实说 我还在想那第一只老鼠会如何
But as I looked out over that city,
但是当我眺望整座城市的时候
nobody knew I was there, nobody could see me,
没人知道我在这 没人可以看见我
no one was even looking.
甚至没人朝我这边看
I had a thought that would guide me for years to come.
我有一个想法 这些年就是它指引着我
Anonymity, Tony.
保持低调 托尼
Thanks to you, it's been my mantra ever since.
多亏了你 这一直是我的座右铭
Right?
对吧?
You simply rule from behind the scenes.
你只需在幕后操控一切
Because the second you give evil a face,
因为当你创造一个恶人的时候
a Bin Laden, a Gaddafi, a Mandarin,
像本拉登 卡扎菲 或是满大人
you hand the people a target.
你给了大家一个宣泄的目标
You're something else.
而你自己可以置身事外
You have met him, I assume?
我猜你见过他了 对吧?
Yes. Sir Laurence Oblivier.
是 奥斯卡非他莫属
I know he's a little over the top sometimes.
我知道他有时候很做作
It's not entirely my fault. He has a tenden...
这不完全是我的错 他习惯于...
He's a stage actor.
他是个舞台剧演员
They say his Lear was the toast of Croydon, wherever that is.
人们说他演的李尔王在那儿挺有名气 无所谓了
Anyway, the point is,
总之 我想说的是
ever since that big dude with the hammer fell out of the sky,
自从那个挥着大锤的家伙从天而降
subtlety has kind of had its day.
低调早已不流行了
What's next for you in your world?
你有什么计划?
I wanted to repay you the selfsame gift that you so graciously imparted to me.
我想报答当初你给我的那份慷慨赠礼
Desperation.
绝望
Now, this is live.
这是直播
I'm not sure if you can tell, but at this moment
我不知你是否发现 但此刻
the body is trying to decide whether to accept EXTREMIS, or just give up.
她的身体正在挣扎 决定是否接受终极生物药剂 或者放弃
And if it gives up,
如果放弃的话
I have to say, the detonation is quite spectacular.
我得说 那爆炸的场景肯定会很壮观的
But until that point, it's really just a lot of pain.
但在那之前 她要一直忍受痛苦的折磨
We haven't even talked salary yet.
我们还没谈报酬呢
What kind of perk package are you thinking of?
你觉得多少小费合适?
Let him go.
放他走
Hold on, hold on.
等等
Maya...
玛雅...
I said, let him go.
我说了 让他走
What are you doing?
你在干什么?
1200 CCs. A dose half of this size, I'm dead.
这是1200CC量的 一半就能致命
It's times like this my temper is tested somewhat.
这种时候真是考验我的脾气啊
Maya, give me the injector.
玛雅 把注射器给我
If I die, Killian,
如果我死了 基利安
what happens to your soldiers? What happens to your product?
你的士兵们怎么办? 你的产品怎么办?
We're not doing this, okay?
别来这套 行吗?
What happens to you? What happens if you go too hot?
你会怎么样? 你如果过热会变成什么样?
The good news is,
好消息就是
a high-level position has just been vacated.
一个高层职位刚刚空出来
You are a maniac.
你是个疯子
No, I'm a visionary.
不 我是梦想家
But I do own a maniac.
我身边确实有个疯子
And he takes the stage tonight.
他今晚还有表演呢
Once we get the Patriot installed,
一旦得到"爱国者"
it will take me nine or 10 minutes for the takedown.
我只需要10分钟就能拆解
That's great, but the last time I looked, there was somebody inside of it.
那好 不过据我所知 里面还有人
Afternoon, gentlemen.
下午好 先生们
Hello, Colonel.
你好 上校
Step aside.
靠边站
We'll get you out of there.
我们会把你弄出来的
Don't worry.
别担心
You'll damage the armour.
你会破坏盔甲的
Yes, I will.
是的
But you can fix it, right?
但你会修好的 对吧?
I'm gonna take the suit to base camp.
我会把盔甲带去大本营
And I want Potts with me.
还要带上波茨小姐
She's still in Phase Two.
可她还在第二阶段
You're not going deaf, are you?
你还没聋吧?
Careful, there. It's a limited edition.
当心点 那个可是限量版
Hey, Ponytail Express.
马尾辫的小哥
What's the mileage count between Tennessee and Miami?
田纳西离迈阿密有多远?
832 miles.
832英里
Very nice.
不错
I'm good like that.
我擅长这个
Can you stop that?
让它别叫了?
Break it, you bought it.
弄坏了你得赔
I think I bought it.
这是我的表了
Okay, that wasn't mine to give away. That belongs to my friend's sister.
好吧 这其实不是我的 这是我朋友妹妹的表
And that's why I'm gonna kill you first.
所以等会我会先收拾你
- What are you gonna do to me?  - You'll see.
- 你会怎么收拾我?  - 你会知道的
You're zip-tied to a bed.
你被捆在床架上了
This.
这样
That.
那样
Are you coming out?
你要出来吗?
Do not open. Do not open. Don't open. Don't open.
别打开 别打开
All right. Let's go.
好吧 打开吧
You... You breathe fire? Okay.
你... 你会喷火? 好吧
It's a glorious day, Savin.
今天是荣耀的日子 赛文
This time tomorrow,
明天的这个时候
I'll have the West's most powerful leader in one hand,
我会控制西方最强大的领袖
and the world's most feared terrorist in the other.
以及最厉害的恐怖分子
I'll own the war on terror.
我会主宰这场反恐战争
Create supply and demand.
创造供求
For you, for your brothers and sisters.
为了你 以及你的兄弟姐妹
Trust me, you're gonna be in a puddle of blood
相信我 你们将会倒在血泊之中
on the ground in five, four, three...
五 四 三...
Come on! Two...
快点! 二...
How did we get this shift?
我们怎么会来看守这活宝的?
All right, I'm gonna give you a chance to escape.
好吧 我给你们一次逃跑的机会
Put down your weapons.
放下武器
Tie yourselves to those chairs. I'll let you live.
把你们自己绑到椅子上 我让你们活命
In five, four, bang!
五 四 嘣!
Wow.
哇
You should be gone by now. You should've already been gone.
你们应该早就跑了 快跑吧
I am just beyond terrified.
我吓得都不敢动了
Here it comes.
来了
- Three, four...  - Shut up.
- 三 四...  - 闭嘴
Five, four, three, two, one!
五 四 三 二 一!
Told you.
早和你说了
Where's the rest?
剩下的跑哪儿去了?
Honestly, I hate working here. They are so weird.
老实说 我讨厌在这儿工作 个个都是怪物
Better late than never.
迟到总比不到好
Not this time. Not the face.
不要 面具别出错
It's good to be back. Hello, by the way.
很高兴再见 你好啊
Hello, sir.
你好 主人
All personnel, Stark is loose and somewhere in the compound.
所有人员注意 斯塔克逃跑 正在建筑某处
Repeat, Stark is loose and somewhere in the compound.
重复 斯塔克逃跑了 正在某处
Let's go!
我们走!
Crap.
该死
Tony?
托尼?
Rhodey, tell me that was you in the suit.
罗迪 告诉我是你在那套盔甲里
No. You got yours?
不 你有盔甲了?
Kind of. Main house, as fast as you can.
算是吧 去主屋 快点
There's somebody I'd like you to meet.
有个人我想让你见见
You, you, you! Move! Get out!
你们! 出去! 快!
The room is secure. I have eyes on the Mandarin.
房间很安全 我已经找到满大人了
What's this? I had winners.
这是什么? 我赢了
What have you come as?
你们是什么人?
You make a move, and I break your face.
你敢动一下 我就打爆你的脸
I never thought people had been hurt. They lied to me.
我从不知道这样会害人 他们骗了我
This is the Mandarin?
这就是满大人?
Yeah, I know, it's... It's embarrassing.
是 我知道... 超尴尬的
Hi, Trevor. Trevor Slattery.
你好 我叫T特雷弗・斯莱特利
I know I'm shorter in person. A bit smaller. Everyone says that.
我知道 我很矮 又很瘦 大家都这么说
But, hey, if you're here to arrest me, there's some people I'd like to roll on.
如果你们想要抓我的话 我得先打个电话
Here's how it works, Meryl Streep.
是这样 大演员
You tell him where Pepper is and he'll stop doing it.
你告诉他佩珀被关哪儿了 他就不会再捉弄你
Doing what?
什么?
I get it! That hurt. I get it! I get it!
我知道了! 好疼的 我全招了!
I don't know about any Pepper, but I know about the plan.
我不认识什么佩珀 但我知道他的计划
- Spill.  - Do you know what they did to my suit?
- 说  - 你知道他们把我的盔甲弄哪儿去了?
What? No.
什么? 不知道
But I do know it's happening off the coast.
但我知道他们在海岸边图谋什么事情
Something to do with a big boat.
和一个大船有关
I can take you there.
我可以带你们去那
Ole', ole', ole', ole'...
哦也 哦也...
Tony, I swear to God, I'm gonna blow his face off.
托尼 我对天发誓 我一定要打爆他的脸
And this next bit may include the vice president as well.
他们下一步行动应该和副总统有关
Is that... Is that important?
这... 有帮助吗?
- Somewhat.  - Yeah, a little bit.
- 算是吧  - 嗯 有一点点
So?
那么?
What are we gonna do?
我们怎么办?
We don't have any transport.
我们连交通工具都没有
Right.
是啊
Hey, Ringo.
嘿 伙计
Didn't you say something about a "lovely speedboat"?
你以前不是说过你有一艘"很酷的快艇"吗?
If he's right about the location, we're 20 minutes from where Pepper is.
如果他说的地方没错 那我们还有20分钟就能到
But we also have to figure out
但我们也得弄清楚
- this vice president thing, right?  - Right.
- 跟副总统有什么关系 对吧?  - 没错
I wonder who I'm calling right now.
我在想我打电话给谁
That's the vice president.
哦 就是副总统
Thanks.
谢谢
Hello?
喂?
Sir, this is Tony Stark.
先生 我是托尼・斯塔克
Welcome back to the land of the living.
欢迎回到活人的世界
We believe you're about to be drawn into the Mandarin campaign.
我们相信您会成为满大人的下一个目标
We gotta get you somewhere safe as soon as possible.
我们得尽快把您带去安全的地方
Mr Stark, I'm about to eat honey-roast ham,
斯塔克先生 我正准备吃蜂蜜烤火腿
surrounded by the Agency's finest.
有一群精干的特工保护我
The president's safe on Air Force One with Colonel Rhodes.
总统和罗迪上校都在空军一号上 很安全
I think we're good, here.
我想我们都没事
Sir, this is Colonel Rhodes.
先生 我是罗迪上校
They're using the Iron Patriot as a Trojan horse.
他们用"钢铁爱国者"当木马
They're gonna take out the president somehow.
他们想绑架总统
We have to immediately alert that plane.
我们得立即通知那艘飞机
Okay, I'm on it. I'll have security lock it down.
好 由我来吧 我会让警卫封锁那片区域
If need be, they can have F-22s in the air in 30 seconds.
如果需要 F22战机会在半分钟内赶到
- Thank you, Colonel.  - Rhodes and Stark out.
- 谢谢上校  - 通话完毕
Everything okay, sir?
没什么事情吧?
Couldn't be better.
再好不过了
I love you, babe.
我爱你 宝贝
Colonel Rhodes.
罗迪上校
Glad to see you could make it, son. I feel safer already.
很高兴见到你 这样我最安全不过了
We gotta make a decision.
我们得做决定了
We can either save the president, or Pepper. We can't do both.
救总统还是救佩珀 我们不可能同时救两个人
Sir, I have an update from Malibu.
主人 马里布有最新消息
The cranes have finally arrived,
起重机终于到了
and the cellar doors are being cleared as we speak.
现在正在清理地下室的门
And what about the suit I'm wearing?
我穿的盔甲呢?
The armour is now at 92%.
目前盔甲充电至92%
That's going to have to do.
只能凑合着用了
Here he comes. Here he comes. Get a quick picture.
他来了 他来了 快给我照一张
Sure.
好的
Everything all right, Colonel?
有事吗 上校?
It is an honour, Mr President.
很荣幸见到您 总统先生
If you're gonna do it, do it!
如果你要杀我 快动手吧!
Cool your boots, sir.
冷静 先生
That's not how the Mandarin works.
这可不是满大人的作风
Sir, Air Force One has been compromised.
长官 空军一号遇袭
Internal shots, temperature spikes.
机身内部发生枪击 温度迅速上升
Get me eyes on it now.
快给我影像
Image coming through now, sir.
图像正在传输 长官
Was that Rhodes?
那是罗迪吗?
Is anyone there?
有人吗?
Let us out!
开门!
The President.
总统在哪里
Now.
快说
He's not here.
他不在这儿
Try the jet stream?
要去喷射气流里找找吗?
Speaking of which, go fish.
说到这个 去钓鱼吧
Walk away from that, you son of a bitch.
从那里走开 你个混蛋
How many in the air?
空中有几个人?
Thirteen, sir.
13个 主人
- How many can I carry?  - Four, sir.
- 我能带几个?  - 4个 主人
Slow down. Slow down, relax. What's your name? Heather?
别紧张 别紧张 放松 你叫什么? 海瑟吗?
Oh, God! No! No!
天啊! 不! 不!
Listen to me. See that guy?
听我说 看到那个人了吗?
I'm gonna swing by, you're just gonna grab him.
我会从他身边滑翔过去 你只要抓住他就行了
- You got it?  - What?
- 懂了吗?  - 什么?
I'll electrify your arm, you won't be able to open your hand.
我会让你的手臂带电 这样你就无法松手了
We can do this, Heather.
你能做到的 海瑟
Easy, see? Eleven more to go.
很简单吧? 还有11个人
Remember that game called Barrel of Monkeys?
记得那个叫猴子捞月的游戏吗?
That's what we're going to do.
这就是我们要做的
18,000 feet.
18,000英尺
Come on, people. Everybody, grab your monkey.
大家加油 每个人都去抓周围的猴子
Nice.
很好
10,000 feet.
10,000英尺
6,000 feet.
6,000英尺
Come on, people.
大伙加油
Come on, come on, come on!
加油 加油 加油!
Yeah!
耶!
1,000 feet.
1,000英尺
400 feet.
400英尺
200 feet, sir.
200英尺 主人
He's a chunky monkey, let's get him.
这是只结实的猴子 抓住他
Hello.
你好
We made it!
我们成功了!
Nice work, guys!
大伙做得不错!
Excellent. Good team effort all around. Go us.
很棒 很好的团队合作 我们都很棒
All right, Jarvis.
好了 贾维斯
But it's only half-done. We've still got to get Pepper...
活儿刚做了一半 我们还得去找佩珀...
That came out of nowhere.
那车从哪冒出来的
Wow.
哇
Give me some good news, man.
老兄 来点好消息
I think they all made it.
我想他们都安全了
Thank God.
谢天谢地
Yeah, but I missed the president.
是啊 但我没找到总统
You couldn't save the president with the suit,
你穿着盔甲都没救出总统
how are we gonna save Pepper with nothing?
现在盔甲毁了 要怎么去救佩珀?
Say, Jarvis, is it that time?
我说 贾维斯 时间到了吗?
The House Party Protocol, sir?
机器人家庭派对计划吗 主人?
Correct.
没错
Hi.
嗨
You think he's gonna help you?
你认为他会帮你?
He won't.
他不会的
Having you here is not just to motivate Tony Stark. It's...
抓你不仅仅是为了刺激托尼・斯塔克 更是...
Well, it's actually more embarrassing than that.
好吧 事实上更难以启齿
You're here as my...
你在这里 算是我的...
Trophy...
战利品...
Good evening, sir.
晚上好 先生
Welcome aboard, Mr President.
欢迎登船 总统先生
Ever hear of an elephant graveyard?
听说过大象坟场吗?
Well, two years ago, the elephant in the room was this scow.
两年前 大象就是这艘船
This is the Roxxon Norco.
这是罗克森・诺克公司的船
And, of course, you'll remember
当然 你肯定记得
that when she spilled a million gallons of crude off Pensacola.
她在彭萨科拉港泄漏了一百万加仑原油
Thanks to you, not one fat cat saw a day in court.
拖你的福 该公司的高官们没人受到制裁
What do you want from me?
你想从我这里得到什么?
Nothing, sir.
我什么都不要 先生
I just needed a reason to kill you that would play well on TV.
我只需要一个杀你的理由 一个能正大光明上电视的理由
You see, I've moved on.
我已经往前看了
I found myself a new political patron,
我找了一个新的政治靠山
and this time tomorrow, he'll have your job.
明天这个时候 他就会接你的班
String him up.
把他吊起来
Hey!
嘿!
Come on.
跟我来
You're not gonna freak out on me, right?
你不会吓坏吧 对吧?
I hope not.
我希望不会
Oh, my God.
天啊
He's strung up over the oil tanker. They're gonna light him up, man.
他被吊在油罐上方 他们打算烧死他 老兄
Viking funeral. Public execution.
维京式葬礼 公开处决
Yeah, death by oil.
没错 被油烧死
Broadcast will commence shortly. Take final positions.
直播即将开始 各就各位
Okay. That's good.
好的 这很好
Now give me cameras A through E and we'll do a full tech rehearsal.
现在调出摄像头A至E 我们做个全面技术彩排
Is your gun up?
你的枪上膛了吗?
Yep. What do I do?
上了 我要怎么做?
Stay on my six, cover high and don't shoot me in the back.
呆在我6点钟方向 注意高处 别朝我背部开枪
Six, high, back. All right.
6点钟 高处 背部 好的
You see that? Nailed it.
你看到了吗? 搞定了
Yeah, you really killed the glass.
是啊 你的确打碎了很多玻璃
You think I was aiming for the bulb?
你认为我瞄准了灯泡?
You can't hit a bulb at this distance.
那么远根本不可能打到灯泡
All personnel, we have hostiles on east unit 12.
全体人员 东12区有敌袭
Over there!
在那里!
- I repeat, hostiles on east unit 12.  - I'm out. Give me...
- 再次重复 东12区有敌袭  - 我没子弹了 给我...
- You got extra magazines?  - They're not universal, Tony.
- 你有多余的弹夹吗?  - 他们不是通用的 托尼
I know what I'm doing, I make this stuff. Give me another one.
我知道我在做什么 我就是做这个的 给我一个弹夹
- One of yours.  - I don't have one that fits that gun.
- 你的拿出来一个  - 我没有配这把枪的弹夹
You've got, like, five of them.
你有的 大概五个
Here's what I'm going to do.
接下来该我了
Save my spot, ready?
帮我望风 好吗?
- What'd you see?  - Too fast. Nothing.
- 看到了什么?  - 太快了 什么都没看到
Here we go.
再来一次
Three guys, one girl, all armed.
三男一女 都有武装
God, I would kill for some armour right now.
天啊 我真希望身上有装甲
- You're right. We need backup.  - Yeah, a bunch.
- 你是对的 我们需要后援  - 是的 很多后援
You know what?
你猜怎么着?
Is that...
那是...
Yep.
没错
- Are those...  - Yeah.
- 那些都是...  - 没错
Merry Christmas, buddy.
圣诞快乐 伙计
Jarvis, target EXTREMIS heat signatures.
贾维斯 瞄准注射了终极生物药剂的热源体
Disable with extreme prejudice.
火力全开 干掉他们
Yes, sir.
是 主人
What are you waiting for? It's Christmas.
还在等什么呢? 今天可是圣诞节
Take them to church.
带他们去见上帝吧
Gentlemen.
先生们
Incoming!
来了!
Jarvis, get Igor to steady this thing.
贾维斯 让伊格尔去把那玩意顶住
This is how you've been managing your down time, huh?
这就是你空闲的时候做的?
Everybody needs a hobby.
每个人都有爱好
Heartbreaker, help Red Snapper out, will you?
心脏终结者 去帮帮红色撕裂者 好吗?
Nice timing.
时间控制得不错
Yeah. That's awesome. Give me a suit, okay?
不错 很酷啊 给我一件盔甲 好吗?
I'm sorry, they're only coded to me.
不好意思 这些只有我能穿
- What does that mean?  - I got you covered.
- 什么意思?  - 我会掩护你的
Good evening, Colonel. Can I give you a lift?
晚上好 上校 我载你一程如何?
Very funny.
真有意思
Sir, I've located Ms Potts.
主人 我找到了波茨小姐
About time.
是时候了
Stop! Put it down. Put it down. Put it down.
别动! 快放下来 放下来 放下来
See what happens when you hang out with my ex-girlfriends?
看到了吧 你和我的前女友们来往的后果?
You're such a jerk.
你真是个混蛋
Yep. We'll talk about it over dinner.
没错 我们吃饭的时候再讨论这个
Come on. A little more, baby.
来 宝贝 再近点
Is this guy bothering you?
那家伙在烦你?
Don't get up.
别起来
Is it hot in there?
里面热吗?
Stuck? Do you feel a little stuck?
卡住了吧? 你有没有觉得有点卡住了?
Like a little turtle, cooking in his little turtle suit.
像在小龟壳里煮小乌龟自己
Tony.
托尼
She's watching.
她在看着呢
I think you should close your eyes.
我觉得你应该闭上眼
Close your eyes.
闭上眼
Close your eyes. You don't want to see this.
闭上眼 你不会想看到这个的
Yeah, you take a minute.
好啊 你歇会儿吧
Jarvis, give me a suit right now!
贾维斯 给我一套盔甲 马上!
Come on!
快点!
Mr President! Just hold on, all right? I'm coming.
总统先生! 坚持住 好吗? 我马上来救您
Just hold on. Hold on.
要坚持住 坚持住
Okay.
好吧
Bye-bye.
再见
Brace yourself.
另一只手抓紧
You look damn good, Mr President,
您看起来真帅 总统先生
but I'm gonna need that suit back.
不过我得要回这件盔甲了
The President is secure, Tony.
总统安全了 托尼
- I'm clearing the area.  - Nice work.
- 我先带他离开这里  - 干得不错
- Ready, sir?  - What do you mean "ready"?
- 准备好了吗 先生?  - 准备好什么?
Pep, I got you. Relax, I got you.
小辣椒 我来了 放松 我来了
Just look at me!
看着我!
Honey, I can't reach any further and you can't stay there.
亲爱的 我只能伸那么远了 你不能呆在那里
All right? You've got to let go.
好吗? 你得松手
You've got to let go! I'll catch you, I promise.
你得松开手! 我会抓住你的 我保证
No!
不!
A shame. I would've caught her.
真丢人 要是我的话 我肯定会抓住她的
Eject.
弹出
Well, here we are on the roof.
很好 我们到了屋顶
Mark 42, inbound.
42号归队
I'll be damned. The prodigal son returns.
真不错 那个浪子居然回来了
Whatever.
随便了
You really didn't deserve her, Tony.
你实在配不上她 托尼
It's a pity. I was so close to having her perfect.
真遗憾 我差点就能让她变得完美了
Okay, okay, wait, wait, wait! Slow down! Slow down!
好吧 好吧 等等 等等! 别过来! 别过来!
You're right. I don't deserve her.
你说得没错 我配不上她
Here's where you're wrong.
但有一点你错了
She was already perfect.
她已经很完美了
Jarvis,
贾维斯
do me a favour and blow Mark 42.
帮我个忙 让42号自爆
No...
不...
No more false faces.
我们都别假惺惺的了
You said you wanted the Mandarin.
你说过你想要找满大人
You're looking right at him.
你面前的就是他
It was always me, Tony. Right from the start.
一直都是我 托尼 从一开始就是
I am the Mandarin!
我就是满大人!
I got nothing.
我手无寸铁
Jarvis, subject at my 12 o'clock is not a target, disengage!
贾维斯 在我12点钟方向的不是目标 解除锁定!
What? What, are you mad at me?
什么? 怎么 你生我气了?
Honey?
亲爱的?
Oh, my God.
天啊
That was really violent.
刚才真暴力
You just scared the devil out of me. I thought you were...
你刚才都吓死我了 我以为你...
I was dead. Why? Because I fell 200 feet?
以为我死了 为什么? 就因为我从200英尺的地方摔下去?
Who's the hot mess now?
谁现在更惨点?
It's still debatable.
有待商榷
Probably tipping your way a little bit. Why don't you dress like this at home?
可能正在向你慢慢倾斜 你在家的时候怎么不穿成这样?
Sport bra. The whole deal.
运动文胸 这一整套真不错
You know, I think I understand why you don't want to give up the suits.
我想我明白为什么你不愿意扔了这些盔甲了
What am I going to complain about now?
我现在还该抱怨什么呢?
Well, it's me.
没事 你的男朋友可是我呢
You'll think of something.
你会找到办法的
- No, don't touch me.  - Don't worry about it.
- 不 别碰我  - 别担心
- No, I'm gonna burn you.  - No, you're not.
- 不 我会烫伤你的  - 不 你不会的
Not hot.
一点都不烫
Am I gonna be okay?
我会变得正常的吧?
No.
不会的
You're in a relationship with me. Everything will never be okay.
你在和我谈恋爱 所有事都不会正常的
But I think I can figure this out, yeah.
但我觉得我能解决这个问题 没错
I almost had this 20 years ago when I was drunk.
20年前我喝醉的时候差点就做出这个了
I think I can get you better.
我觉得我会让你恢复的
That's what I do. I fix stuff.
这就是我的工作 修理东西
And all your distractions?
那些让你分心的东西呢?
Eh... I'm going to shave them down a little bit.
呃... 我会减少一点点他们的数量
Jarvis. Hey.
贾维斯
All wrapped up here, sir. Will there be anything else?
麻烦都解决了 主人 还有其他事吗?
You know what to do.
你知道该做什么
The Clean Slate Protocol, sir?
库存清理计划吗 主人?
Screw it, it's Christmas. Yes, yes.
管他呢 今天是圣诞节 是的 没错
Okay, so far? Do you like it?
目前为止还行吧? 你喜欢吗?
It will do.
很满意
And so, as Christmas morning began, my journey had reached its end.
于是 随着圣诞节早晨的到来 我的旅程走到了终点
You start with something pure,
开始时毫无功利
something exciting. Then, come the mistakes.
满怀热情 然后开始犯错
The compromises.
还有妥协
We create our own demons.
我们创造了自己的恶魔
Great to see you! Bloody hell!
很高兴见到你们! 真见鬼!
As promised, I got Pepper sorted out. It took some tinkering.
我答应过要帮佩珀恢复正常 但要做点手术
But then I thought to myself, "Why stop there?"
但之后我就想 "为什么止步于此呢?"
Of course, there are people who say progress is dangerous,
当然 有人说过程很危险
but I'll bet none of those idiots ever had to live with a chestful of shrapnel.
但我打赌这些蠢货中没有一个人曾带着满胸膛的弹片活着
And now, neither will I.
现在 我也不会了
Let me tell you,
我告诉你
that was the best sleep I'd had in years.
那是多年来我睡得最香的时候
It's okay. It's okay.
没事的 没事的
It's okay.
没事的
No, look.
不是 快看
土豆枪II代 你的伙伴 机械师
So, if I were to wrap this up, tie it with a bow, or whatever...
如果我要做一番总结 鞠个躬 或别的什么...
I guess I'd say my armour, it was never a distraction,
我猜我会说 我的盔甲从来都不是分心之物
or a hobby.
也不是兴趣
It was a cocoon.
它是一个茧
And now,
而现在
I'm a changed man.
我破茧化蝶了
You can take away my house, and all my tricks and toys.
你可以夺走我的房子 我所有的把戏和玩具
One thing you can't take away...
但有一样你是夺不走的...
I am Iron Man.
我就是钢铁侠
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 咳嗽的小鱼 捞盐 ICL的RK翔 海盗爱热水 千欲 汐颜
校对: 柚子茶 影子
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 咳嗽的小鱼 捞盐 ICL的RK翔 海盗爱热水 千欲 汐颜
校对: 柚子茶 影子
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 咳嗽的小鱼 捞盐 ICL的RK翔 海盗爱热水 千欲 汐颜
校对: 柚子茶 影子
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 咳嗽的小鱼 捞盐 ICL的RK翔 海盗爱热水 千欲 汐颜
校对: 柚子茶 影子
You know, and thank you by the way. For listening.
你懂的 还有 多谢倾听
Plus, something about getting it off my chest,
再者 敞开心扉
and putting it out there in the atmosphere instead of holding this in...
一吐为快 而不是憋在...
I mean, this is what gets people sick, you know.
我是说 憋着不说人们才会生病
Wow, I had no idea you were such a good listener.
哇 之前我都不知道你这么擅长聆听
To be able to share all my intimate thoughts
能和人分享我所有的
and my experiences with someone,
想法和经历
it just cuts the weight of it in half.
身上的压力都减半了
You know, it's like a snake swallowing its own tail.
就像一条蛇去咬自己的尾巴
Everything comes full circle.
所有事都圆满了
And the fact that you've been able to help me process...
而且你还能帮我梳理...
- Are you with me?  - Sorry... I was, yeah.
- 你在听吗?  - 对不起... 我刚刚 呃
We were at...
我们刚刚说到...
Are you actively napping?
你睡着了?
I was... I... I drifted.
我刚刚... 我... 我走神了
Where did I lose you?
从什么地方开始的?
Elevator in Switzerland.
瑞士的电梯
So, you heard none of it.
那你什么都没听到
I'm sorry. I'm not that kind of doctor.
不好意思 我不是那种医生
I'm not a therapist.
也不是治疗师
- It's not my training.  - So?
- 我没受过那样的训练?  - 然后?
- I don't have the...  - What? The time?
- 我没有...  - 什么? 时间?
Temperament.
性情
You know what? Now that I think about it...
你知道嘛? 既然我想到它...
God, my original wound.
天啊 我最早的伤疤
- 1983, all right?  - Yes.
- 1983年 对吧?  - 没错
I'm 14 years old, I still have a nanny. That was weird.
我那年14岁 还有个保姆 真诡异